派拉蒙电影公司
出 品
协助出品
孩之宝
我们曾是一群崇尚和平的智能机器人
We were once a peaceful race of intelligent mechanical beings.
但为自由而战的汽车人
But then came the war.
和梦想独裁的霸天虎之间
Between the autobots who fought for freedom,
发生了战争
and the decepticons who dreamt of tyranny.
力量和数量的悬殊
Over matched, and out numbered.
我们的溃败已成定局
Our defeat was all but certain.
但在战争结束之前
But in the wars final days,
一艘汽车人战舰逃离了战场
one autobot ship escaped the battle.
其上装载了神秘货物
It was carrying a secret cargo,
它能改变整个星球的命运
which would have changed our planets fate.
一项绝地任务
A desperate mission.
我们最后的希望
Our final hope.
这个希望  破灭了
A hope, that vanished.
1961年  新墨西哥州  国家射电天文台射电望远镜巨阵
一个放在上面
One up there.
一个放在那边  下面再放一个
One over there. One more down there.
发现什么了
Whatcha got?
检测到撞击
Impact detected.
确认出现撞击
We have impact confirmed.
接触地外智慧
Contacted.
弗吉尼亚兰利  美国航空航天局局长
-格林威治时间22点50分  -什么
- 22:50 GMT. - What?
马上给我接国防部长
Give me SEC-DED on the phone right away.
紧急通知
发现外太空活动轨迹
侦测月球发生撞击
于格林威治时间22:50接触地外智慧
五角大楼指挥中心
麦克纳马拉先生  总统在等您
Mr. McNamara, the President is expecting you.
-让博比进来  -总统先生
- Get Bobby in here. - Mr. President.
最高机密
Designation, top secret.
我们认为有不明飞行物在月球坠毁
We believe a UFO has crashed into the moon.
苏联应该也在行动
We think the Russians are on to it as well.
那你让航空航天局竭尽全力
Well then you tell NASA to move heaven and earth.
我们要上月球
We need to get to the moon.
我们准备尝试载人航天计划
We're going to attempt a manned mission.
航空航天局预计要花五年时间
NASA said it would take five years.
总之要赶在苏联前面
You get there before the Russians.
我认为我国应全力以赴
I believe that this nation should commit itself,
实现这一目标
to achieving the goal.
-倒数十五秒  -在七零年代之前
- Fifteen seconds. - Before this decade is out,
让人类成功登月
of landing a man on the moon,
并安全返回地球
and returning him safely to the earth.
发射倒计时
Ignition sequence starts
五  四  三
Five, four, three,
八年后  1969年7月16日
二  一
two, one.
点火
And ignition.
发射升空  成功升空了
Lift off, we have a lift off.
九点三十二分
Thirty two minutes past the hour.
阿波罗11号升空  三号航空塔台
Lift off on Apollo 11, tower three.
尼尔·阿姆斯特朗报告  阿波罗11号航向正确
Neil Armstrong reporting Apollo 11 on proper heading.
凭借土星五号运载火箭喷出巨大火焰
Apollo 11 is on the way.
阿波罗11号正在驶向
Riding that pillar of flame from the Saturn five.
二十五万英里外
Out there 250,000 miles away,
月球正等着人类的第一次探访
where the moon is waiting for man's first arrival.
休斯顿  准备降落  完毕
Houston you're a go for landing, over.
离地四十英尺  下降2.5  扬起一些灰尘
40 feet, down 2 1/2. Kicking up some dust.
三十英尺  下降2.5  看到微弱的阴影
Thirty feet, two and a half down. Faint shadow
向前4  向右漂移一些
Four Forward. Drifting to the right a little.
二十英尺  下降0.5
20 feet, down a half.
开着陆灯
Contact light.
关闭引擎
Okay, engine stop.
休斯顿  到达静海基地  着陆成功
Houston, tranquility base here, The Eagle has landed.
与月球第一次实时视频连线
收到你着陆的消息  鹰
We copy you down, Eagle.
大家都为你们担心
You got a bunch of guys about to turn blue.
现在终于可以松口气了
We're breathing again.
最高机密
今天约四亿观众在观看直播
Perhaps 400 million persons are watching this broadcast today,
这是我们这个时代最伟大的事情
of the greatest event in our time.
是人类有史以来最伟大的事情之一
And one of the great events of all recorded history.
我已经下到梯子底端
I'm at the foot of the ladder.
准备踏上月球
I'm going to step on to land now.
这是我个人的一小步
That's one small step for man,
但却是全人类的一大步
one giant leap for mankind.
-准备好了吗  -对  长官
- Are we good? - Yes sir.
第一步的秘密时间是 1092
Unofficial time on the first step 1092....
阿波罗11号  这里是休斯顿  完毕
Apollo 11? This is Houston, over.
鹰  我们受到信号干扰
Eagle we're getting a signal interference.
收到了吗
Do you copy?
已证实  与阿波罗11号失去联系
We now have a confirmation. Loss of signal from Apollo 11.
此时阿波罗11号在月球另一端
The Apollo 11 is for the moment, on the far side of the moon.
尼尔  别人听不到你了
Neil, you are dark on the rock.
执行任务
Mission is a go.
你有二十一分钟
You have 21 minutes.
请准备  还剩三分四十五秒
Please stand by, 3 minutes and 45 seconds and counting.
我的天啊
My god.
是一张巨大的金属脸
It's some sort of giant metal face.
天啊
Jesus.
控制中心  我们已进入战舰内部
Control, we are inside the ship.
受损严重
Extensive damage.
体积太大  无法全面检查
Way to big to check the entire ship.
休斯顿  里面无人生还
Everything is dead in here, Houston.
没有生命迹象
No signs of life anywhere.
这些东西真大
These thing are massive.
收到
We copy.
你们还剩七分钟氧气
You got seven minutes on your oxygen.
我们不是宇宙里唯一的智慧生命  是吗
We are not alone after all, are we.
对  长官
No, sir.
我们不是唯一的
We're not alone.
好了  总统先生请讲
All right, go ahead Mr. President.
尼尔  波兹
Hello, Neil, Buzz.
我现在白宫办公室
I'm talking to you by telephone
跟你们通话
from the oval room at the White House.
这绝对是值得记入史册的
And this certainly has to
一次通话
be the most historic telephone call ever made.
我们所有人都为你们感到无比骄傲
I just can't tell you how proud we all are.
对每个美国人来说  这是一生中最值得骄傲的日子
For every American, this has to be the proudest day of our lives.
由于你们所做的一切
Because of what you have done.
我们已溅落
We have splashed down.
天空成为人类世界的一部分
The heavens has become a part of man's world.
在整个人类历史上
For one priceless moment.
在这宝贵一刻
In all of history of man.
地球全人类都真心一致
All the people on this earth are truly one.
为你们所做的一切感到自豪
Along with their pride in which you have done.
你们鼓舞我们更加努力
You've inspired us to redouble our efforts,
为人类带来和平与宁静
to bring peace and tranquility to Earth.
变形金刚
月黑之时
我的英雄  该醒了
My hero, needs to wake up.
这是什么
What is that?
这是你新的幸运兔
This is your new lucky bunny.
卡莉  想法不错
Yeah, it's a beautiful thought, Carly.
但我觉得兔子不是全身都幸运
But I don't think it's the whole, uh, bunny that's lucky.
只有这部分
You see it's just this section here.
只有兔子脚是幸运的
You see it's just the rabbit's foot that's lucky.
好吧  不过是个吉祥物罢了
All right, it's just a good luck charm.
让你乐观点
Hmm, help you think positive.
今天很重要
Today's important.
快起来
Come on, get up.
-戴那条好领带  -好
- Hey, wear that nice tie. - Yeah.
你要钱吃午饭吗
You need any money for lunch?
不用  我不用钱
No, I don't need any money for lunch.
我有昨天午饭省下的钱
I have money from yesterday's lunch.
你喜欢这样  是吗
You love it, don't you.
我不过是你的美国小白脸
I'm just your American boy-toy.
我心爱的小白脸
A lover boy-toy.
你知道这有多郁闷吗  我拯救了这世界两次
You know how demoralizing it is to save the world twice,
还要卑躬屈膝去找个工作
to be groveling for a job.
别人又不知道你拯救过世界  山姆
They don't know you saved the world, Sam.
我知道  我信你
I mean I do, I believe you.
政府知道  他们可以通过关系在华盛顿给我安排个工作
Government knows, they could hook me up with a job right here in D.C.
我应该和汽车人一起工作
I mean I should be working with the autobots.
不然太不公平了
Otherwise, it's not fair.
好啦  他们供你念完了大学
Come on, they paid for your college.
总统颁给你一块英雄奖章
The president gave you a hero medal.
谢谢  小伙子  干得不错
Thank you, man. Great job.
这是我经历中最棒的事情
That's the coolest thing that ever happened to me.
好了  伙计们
All right, guys.
看看这东西
What the fuck!
而且我记得
And as I recall
这还不是那天的高潮
that wasn't even the highlight of your day.
大使先生  给
Mr. Ambassador, here.
下一个  英国大使馆
British Embassy you're up next.
-其实不  -不  你不能戴着
- It's not really... - No, you don't wear it.
-我就算想也不能  -放在这
- I couldn't even if I wanted to. - Leave it there.
放在盒子里
Leave it in the box, right.
收在盒子里  这盒子真漂亮
You keep it in there, what a gorgeous box.
对  我的奖章
Oh yeah, my medal.
你知道谁给我的吗
You know who gave that to me?
谁
Who?
白宫内部对美国总统的称谓缩略语
-博图士  -噢
- POTUS. - Oh.
美国总统
The President of the United States.
所有人都很难找工作
Hey, it's hard for everybody to get a job.
我没时间了
I don't have time.
我爸妈自驾游把世界玩了个遍
You see, my parents are going to be here in a week.
一周后就会到这儿
on their road-trip party world tour.
我爸就要来了  我却没个工作
My dad gets here, and I don't have a job.
他绝对会抽我  我时间不多了
He's gonna spank me you know. It's go time for me.
好吧  今晚我给你个工作
All right, tonight I'll give you a job.
为我准备一顿浪漫的晚餐
Romance me with a nice dinner and, uh...
也许我会给你奖励
maybe you'll get that bonus.
█
小诸葛：汽车人成员
联想 ThinkPad Edge
精锐版笔记本
-看到啦  -快滚开
- Get lucky. - Get out of here.
等等  别  别
Wait, no, no, no, no, no.
他太恶心了
Oh, he's gross.
她很火辣哦
She's good.
他们被困在这里
They've been stranded here,
得有人看着他们
somebody's got to watch out for them, you know.
昨天他还藏在我内衣橱里
Yesterday that one was in my underwear drawer.
查看了一下  看起来也都不错
Did research, looking real good too.
-不用打我吧  -你这个男朋友真不正常
- No need to hit me - You are not a normal boyfriend.
可你就爱我这点  不是吗
That's what you love about me, isn't it?
真是个爱哭鬼
Heh, what a cry baby.
我还没说过那个字呢
You know I don't have the word yet.
要是你能分摊房租  我可能就说了
Maybe a little bit closer when you can pay your half of the rent.
拜
Bye.
在外面都特么让我短路了
Frinking shorting my circuits out here.
█
转轮：汽车人成员
儿童遥控玩具越野车
你这样做真不人道
It's inhumane, what it is.
让我们住在阳台的盒子里
Make us live in a box on a balcony.
旁边还是头畜生
Right next to a beast.
-把我当动物养吗  -行了  住嘴
- Like a common animal. - Stop, okay.
你和你那神经朋友
You and your creepy sidekick,
没有允许不能进来
you can't be in here without permission.
谁说的  那个金发小妞吗
According to who, Miss blondy-blonde?
小狗狗  进去
Get out little doggie.
里恩  咋样
Yo, Brain's wassup?
还行
Doing good.
真烦  我看过这段
Ah shit, I'd seen this one.
史波克就在这发疯
It's the one where Spock goes nuts.
山姆  我不知道搬来和这小妞同住会怎样
You know Sam, I don't know about moving in with this chick.
要是她像上个姑娘一样把我们甩了呢
Uh, what if she dumps us like the last girl?
我不喜欢她  太凶了
What she was mean, didn't like her.
我们得团结起来
Us guys got to stick together.
我们是一家人
We are family
不  我们不是一家人  你们是政治难民
No, we're not family. You're a political refugee.
而我终于找到真正喜欢我的人
And I have finally found someone who appreciates me for me.
那你告诉她  我们不是宠物
Well you tell her that we're not your pets.
也不是玩具
And we're not your toys.
我们是高等智能外星种族
All right, we're an advanced genius alien race,
只想找个安身之处
just looking for a home.
-也许这不是个好主意  -没必要停在这
- Maybe it wasn't such a good idea.  - Didn't have to stop.
得了吧  他们能拿我们怎么办  拖走吗
Come on, what are they going to do, tow it?
他在哪
Where is he?
塞米
Sammy!
-行了  很好笑  -山姆
- Oh, come on that's funny, ha, ha. - Sam.
我想死你们了
I miss you guys so much.
当然  怎么样
Sure you did, what do you think?
-真不错  -可爱吧
- Look at that. - Cute.
-你看起来真老  -闭嘴
- You look old. - Stop it.
感觉我看到末日了
Feel like I can see the end.
领带很漂亮
Oh I love your little tie.
我媳妇呢
Hey, where's my girl?
-我那美丽的卡莉呢  -她在工作  老妈
- where's my beautiful Carly? - She's at work, Ma.
-她找了个新工作  -是嘛
- She's got a new job. - Right.
我以为你们一周以后才到
I thought you were going to be here in a week.
是21号不是11号  老爸你告诉我的
The 21st not the 11th, Dad remember?
我们就是改变主意了
We just hauled ass in this thing.
-我们停下来加油  -这宝贝车  跑得飞快
- We stopped for gas.  - This thing . The love tub, it flies.
我们耽误你什么事了吗
Oh, are we keeping you from something?
比如  工作
Like say, your job.
也该找到了
Well it's about time.
我们很担心
You had us worried.
我  我有面试
Uh, I have, uh, job interviews.
那挺好啊
Oh, that's good.
-糟透了  -别说这话
- That sucks. - Stop it.
你不用这么悲观  爸爸
You don't have to be so negative dad, you know.
你到了华盛顿  和你儿子  家人在一起
You're in DC, you're here with your son, your family.
这是多美好的时光
I mean it's good times.
你没有工作  这太糟了
It sucks that you don't have a job.
-这也有很多好玩的地方  不是吗  -对啊
- Good things to do here too, right? - Yeah.
去看博物馆  还有纪念碑  好吗
Right, museums and monuments, okay.
-晚上见  -我去准备礼物
- I'll see you tonight. - I'm bagging the gift.
山姆  我认为你去面试得穿条正式的裤子
Sam, I think for an interview you should wear real pants.
我认为一辈子都应该穿正式的裤子
I think for life you should wear real pants.
大黄蜂怎么了
Oh, wha...what happened to Bumble Bee?
他出去执行任务了  我得拿这辆备用
He's off on his missions, I had to get this as a back-up.
你的车找到工作了
Oh, your car has a job, huh?
这车会变成什么
What does it change into?
什么都不会变
It doesn't change into anything.
是个收藏家的藏品  便宜得很
It's a collectors' item, I got it for a steal.
只是需要修整一下  真的
It just needs some work, trust me.
挺不错的  挺像大黄蜂
Oh, I think it's darling. It reminds me a lot of Bumble Bee.
如果大黄蜂也是堆废铁的话
If Bumble Bee were a sad piece of shit.
来  我们送你去
Come on we'll give you a ride.
在我们到来以后
In the years since our arrival.
我们的新家地球  变化巨大
Our new home, Earth had seen much change.
能量块探测器保卫着地球上的城市
Energon detectors guard its cities now.
█
擎天柱：汽车人首领
彼得比尔特牵引卡车头
Peterbilt.389
远程防御系统监视着天空
Long range defense systems watch the skies.
中东非法核工厂
现在我们帮助盟军
So now we assist our allies,
解决人类的冲突
in solving human conflicts.
防止人类伤害自己
To prevent mankind from bringing harm to itself.
是国防部长的车
快放行
█
恐龙：汽车人成员
法拉利458 Italia跑车
趴下  最好呆在原地别动
On the ground. Per favour, and stay there.
█
大黄蜂：汽车人成员
2010款雪佛兰卡马洛概念车
CHEVROLET.Camaro
我们组成秘密部队在全球执行各种任务
We work in secret teams on various missions around the globe.
同时  寻找我们真正敌人
And all the while, we search for signs,
回归的迹象
of our true enemies return.
我是瓦斯科特
I am Voshkod,
隶属乌克兰能源部总理事会
General Council with Ukrainian Department of Energy.
我方政府会正式否认
My government will officially deny
我们有过本次谈话
that we're having this conversation.
在一栋净化设施里有所发现
At one of our decontamination facilities a discovery was made,
恐怕那实际是外星人
which I fear may be alien in nature.
这栋设施的名字是切尔诺贝利
The Facility's name is, Chernobyl.
█
━
切尔诺贝利核电站
前苏联修建的第一座核电站
1986年4月26日起火报站
瓦斯科特先生
Mr. Voshkod.
自86年起无人居住
Uninhabited since '86.
我听说接下来两万年也不适合居住
I hear it won't be livable again for another 20,000 years.
至少那么长时间  乌克兰是片肥沃的土地  这是个悲剧
At least. Ukraine was the most fertile land, it's a tragedy.
在这边
This way.
佩戴保护装置  我们有60分钟执行任务
Gear up, we have 60 minutes on the ground.
注意辐射等级
Watch your radiation levels.
瓦斯科特先生  您的保护装置呢
Mr. Voshkod, where's your protective gear?
您的保护装置呢
Where's your protective gear?
无所谓
It would not matter.
对我是迟早的事
For me it's only a matter of time.
穿过学校
Through the school.
尤里会带你们下去
Uri will take you below.
上校  单独跟你说件事
And one other thing, Colonel, in private.
这里曾做过能量实验
There were some energy experiments...
等下再说
It can wait.
继续前进  别掉队
Keep moving, stay tight.
好  就是这  把灯打开
Okay, right here. Bring up the light.
长官  有发现
Officer, we got a visual.
发现一不明物体  被夹在在金属控制线上
Looks like the object's clamped in some kind of metal harness.
这是什么
What's this?
伙计们
Guys,
为什么这东西上面有前苏联空间项目的标志
Why does this thing have Soviet space program markings on it?
-人造卫星  -检测到能量源  长官
- Sputnik. - Energon readings, sir.
水平很高
It's strong.
在我们底下
Below us.
来得很快
It's coming fast.
█
震荡波：霸天虎成员
来自赛博坦的恐怖生物
遇敌  遇敌
Contact, contact!
快上去  快  快
Get topside now! Move, move, move!
追  追
Let's go, let's go!
上武器  重武器
Weapons up! Heavy weapons up!
大家退后
Stay behind me.
快跑  快跑
Move, move!
擎天柱
Optimus!
撤退
Fall back!
这东西包围我们了
It's circling around us!
它在攻击我们的右翼
It's taking out flank.
用重型武器攻击
Get the heavy weapons.
擎天柱
Optimus.
这是啥东西
What the hell was that thing?
那是震荡波
That is Shockwave.
他为什么要这个
Why was he after this?
这不可能
It's impossible.
这是引擎零件
This is an engine part.
来自一架失踪已久的汽车人战舰
From a long lost autobot ship.
█
激光鸟：霸天虎成员
具有多种变形模式
合作愉快
Pleasure working with you.
面试  太激动了
Interviews. This is so exciting.
宝贝  要口香糖吗
Honey, do you want some gum?
你紧张的时候口气不太好
Your breath gets really gnarly when you're nervous.
威特维奇先生
Mr. Whit-wickey.
在这  不用找了
Yep, the search is over.
我是惠特利
I'm Mr. Whitley.
-还有其他人吗  -没有
- Is any one else joining? - No.
没了
No?
-要我坐过去吗  我可以坐过去  -最好不要
- Want me to move right there, I'm moving right there. - I prefer not.
先生
Sensei.
准备好了吗  开始
Ready, begin.
我今年毕业
Uh, graduated this year
专业是地缘政治学  辅修科技研究
majored in geo politics, minor in tech studies..
对政府和科技很感兴趣
Very interested in government technologies,
研究他们如果相互影响
how that's gonna intersect and co-exist.
决定未来
Shape the future.
我们干嘛把他送去常春藤大学
Why did we bother sending him to an Ivy College for?
毕业三个月了  还找不到工作
Three months out of school and he can't find a job.
-松宝先生  -松本
- Mr. Matsu-piece-u. - Matsu Moto
-松门  -松本
- Masi Moto - Masu Moto.
-玛莎  我能称您为玛莎吗  -不能
- Martha, can I call you Martha? - No, you may not.
好的  杰克  世界上有两种人
Okay. Jack, there's two type of people in this world.
一种是思想者  一种是行动者
There's thinkers and there's doers.
还有胜者  梦想者和伙伴
There's winners, there's dreamers and there's buddies.
说下你的弱点吧
What about, some weaknesses.
我没有
I don't. . .
您看上去很值得人信任
You have a very trustworthy face.
让我想起  亚洲版的桑德斯上校[肯德基创始人]
You remind of like a... an Asian Colonel Sanders.
我能信任的人
A man I can trust.
这是新千年一代  就像之前迷惘的一代
It's a millennial, you know like some kind of lost generation.
联邦调查局为什么要找你
Why was the FBI looking for you?
什么
The what?
对  FBI  你能注意到这点真厉害
Yeah, FBI. Good of you to flag that.
谁十四岁没幻想过外星人呢
Did you ever have any alien craziness when you were fourteen.
他们很友好  很快就找到我了
They were very kind to me, found me in a jiffy.
这些记录都销毁了
Uh, and that's all been expunged.
后来奥巴马还给我颁了块奖章
Obama get me a medal, actually.
说起来
Just saying.
招一个得过奖章的人总是不错
It's always good to have a medal guy in the office, with a medal.
-从奥巴马手里  -对
- From Obama? - Yeah.
奥巴马是美国民主党人
这公司里大多是共和党人
In this office, we're mostly Republicans.
不好意思
So.
-我感觉不太好  -不好吗
- I'm not feeling to good. - No.
-不好  -干嘛不去拿个餐盘
- No. - Why don't you get a little dipping tray.
把热狗泡在汽水里  问题就解决了
And dip the dog in the pepto, that's the solution.
老爸  我还有一个面试  我们得走了  快点
Pow, I got another one, we gotta go, come on.
有没搞错
Really?
坐
Sit.
来了一个山姆·威特维奇先生
Got myself a Mr. Sam Witwicky,
刚毕业
recent college graduate.
之前的工作经历几乎为零
Previous experience next to zero.
但是  却有我们董事会的推荐信
Yet, he has a recommend letter from our board.
这特么真稀奇
W.T.F. to that.
你们董事会有我认识的人吗
Do I know somebody on your board?
事情是这样的  我们很清楚自己的身份
Here's the deal, we know who we are.
艾奇利塔系统是电信业和航空业的佼佼者
Accuretta systems is called the leader in telecom, aerospace.
去年盈利一百七十亿
17 billion on profit last year.
我们和航空航天局
We contract for DOP, NASA,
喷气推进实验室等等都有合同
JPL you name it.
你在这干  前途无量
You perform here, doors open for you anywhere.
小子  大学毕业后的第一份工作至关重要
And what, first job out of college is critical, kid.
你要么选对行业前途无量
You either take a step down the correct career path.
要么跌入一生爬不出来的万丈深渊
Or you fall into a life sucking abyss.
那么这全取决于你对我下面说的三个字的反应
So it all depends on how you respond to my next two words.
打动我
Impress me.
现在
Now?
打动我
Impress me.
我完全没准备  我
You catch me off guard, I...
打动我
Impress me.
我知无不言  您尽管问
I'm an open book, ask me any question you like.
-所以你是个野心家  勇往直前  -是的
- So you're a go-getter, ramrod. - Yes sir.
有控制欲的人
Take charge kind of guy.
我像个杀手  冷血杀手
I'm a killer, a stone cold killer.
是有控制欲的人
So, take charge guy.
爱掌控  维京海盗  野蛮人
Take charge, Viking, barbarian.
对  这些都是我
Of course, it's me.
我就是这样
Pow! I'm here.
我们要的不是那种人
We are not looking for that here.
不要马屁精
No brown nosing, no suck up.
不要笨蛋
No toolery, I...
喂  布拉索思先生
Yes, Mr. Brazos.
为什么傻女用的好象是
Um, why is Chantal using what appears to be,
红色层的红杯子
a red cup from the red floor?
-我们可是黄色层  -我来处理
- When we are on the yellow floor. - I'm on it.
这很直观因此是一种粗俗的表现
It is a visual and therefore a visceral betrayal.
阻止她
Stop it.
真是个蠢货
Such a dumb ass.
恶心
Disgusting.
谢了
Thank you.
太没组织纪律了
It's a total anarchy around here.
电邮上说职位是行政助理
The uh, email I read said administrative aid.
不  是收发室
Nope, mail room.
我还是告辞了
I'm going to go.
你知道有多少常春藤毕业生
Uh, do you have any idea how many Ivy league,
和优等生想尽办法
Phi Beta Kappa's would kill...
先生  我曾两次救过您的命
Mister I saved your life twice.
明白吗  我不能告诉你何时怎样
Okay, I can't tell you how or when.
或为何  但我的确做了
Or why, but I have done shit that matters.
我只想再找个需要我的工作
And I'd just kinda like a job where I matter again.
所以谢了  我不干
So thank you, but no thank you.
-好吗  -知道我怎么想吗
- Okay. -You know what I think?
你想要的工作将在这个工作以后出现
You want the job after this job.
可是孩子  这份工作是你必经的一站
But son, this is the job that's standing in your way.
这就是为何你能非常胜任这个工作
And that's why you're going to be so very, very good at it.
因为当我看着你
'Cause when I look at you.
仿佛看见年轻的自己
I see a younger me.
华盛顿特区  机密鸟巢总部
美国卫生及公共服务部
所有到达的汽车人进行检修
All arriving Autobots in par,
十五分钟后开始训练和汇报
training and debriefing in 15 minutes.
意大利人在二十三号车位报告
Dino report to bay 23.
横炮在三十七号车位进行武器测试
Sideswipe bay 37 for weapons assessment.
参议员  希望你记住  每当航天航空局
Senator, I suggest you remember that when the NASA
...需要资金  他们就给我打电话
...wants funding they call me.
中央情报局执行任务之前
When the CIA is going to take out a target.
也要得到我的许可
They ask first for my permission.
总统想知道哪位国会议员
When the President wants to know
在政治上不坚定
which members of Congress are politically vulnerable.
比如说未经发现的犯罪行为
In terms of oh, let's say undiscovered criminal conduct.
也会问过我
I'm on their memory dials.
美政府表示他们正对爆炸进行监视
USA agency say they have been monitoring the blast.
美国有线新闻网  伊朗发生工业事故
可事实上这是一起秘密军事袭击
But in fact this was a covert military strike.
目前没有任何国家表示为这起爆炸负责
No nation has yet claimed ownership.
中央情报局为中东发生的这起
The CIA is up my ass about this mystery...
神秘爆炸事件对我纠缠不休
..raid in the middle east.
是时候坦白了  部队是否参与此事
So it's time to come clean, was the unit involved?
不太清楚  女士
Uh, I'm not sure, Ma'am.
大家看好  就是这样对霸天虎
All right guys, this is how you do a Decepticon...
的头部进行致命攻击
...head kill shot.
作为国家情报局的指挥官
As director of National Intelligence,
我喜欢有点脑子的答案
I'm a really big fan of intelligent answers.
我  我实在不能明确回答您
I...I can't really tell you definitively.
这些汽车人就像十几岁的孩子
These Autobots are like teenage kids.
喜欢时不时地溜出去
They like to sneak out of the house once in a while.
兰诺克斯上校  你究竟是不是指挥官
Colonel Lennox, are you in command or are you not?
是的  女士  我是
Yes, Ma'am. I am....
别叫我女士  受够了
Stop with the Ma'am, enough with the Ma'am.
我看起来有那么老吗
Do I look like a Ma'am?
没有  女士
No, ma'am.
是  女士  是
Yes, ma'am, yes.
-这是我最好的一件发明  铁皮   -不错
- This one is a perfect invention, Ironhide. - Right.
太好了  你们来了
Oh, good you're here.
█
Q：汽车人成员
梅赛德斯 奔驰E5500跑车
我叫Q  希望你们能解答他的疑问
My name's Que. I do hope you have answers for him.
我从没见过他这么心烦
I've never seen him so upset.
擎天柱  记得夏洛特·米樱吧
Optimus, you remember Charlotte Mearing?
国家情报局的主管
Our director of National Intelligence.
他心情不好
He's in a bad mood.
他今天谁都不想理
He's a not want to talk-a to anybody today.
这算什么
What is this?
安静疗法吗
The silent treatment?
我们见过那种  这次不是
We've seen that, and this is not that.
█
铁皮：汽车人成员
通用CMC中型商用车
GMC.4500.Topkick
-绝对不是  -这次更糟
- Definitely not. - This is worse.
擎天柱  你自己说
Prime, make something of yourself.
他很生气
He's pissed.
你们骗了我们
You lied to us.
你们告诉我们
Everything humans' know of our planet
说已经共享了所有对我们星球已知的情况
we were told had all been shared.
那为什么人类的土地上会发现这玩意
So why was this found in human possession?
这事儿我们也不知道
We were in the dark on this also.
今天以前只有主管能进入第7区
It was director only clearance at Sector 7, until now.
-把包拿来  -哪个包
- The bag. - Which bag?
铂金女士包  绿色鸵鸟皮的
Hermes Birkin, green ostrich.
真受不了
Oh my god.
这是个鲜为人知的秘密
This is a secret few men knew.
知情人也死得差不多了
And fewer still remain alive.
请允许我向你介绍
Allow me to please introduce to you,
建立航空航天局的两位主管
two of NASA's founding mission directors.
以及宇航员  波兹·阿尔德林博士
and astronaut, Dr. Buzz Aldrin.
最先登陆月球的两人之一  长官
One of the first two men to step foot on the moon. Sir.
擎天柱
Optimus Prime.
作为后进的宇宙旅行者
From a fellow space traveler.
见到你很荣幸
It's a true honor.
我也很荣幸
The honor is mine.
我们整个六十年代的太空竞赛
Our entire space race of the 1960's...
好像都是对某一事件的回应
...it appears was in response to an event.
我方宇航员对一架坠毁的外星飞船进行调查
Our astronauts investigated a crashed alien ship.
舱内无人生还
No survivors on board.
在总指挥的命令下  我们发誓对一切保密
We were sworn to secrecy by our commander in chief.
这是一项永不能提及的任务
This was a mission you will never speak of.
明白  长官
I understand, sir.
航空航天局里共有35人知道真正的计划
A total of 35 people knew the real plan at NASA.
苏联人成功向月球发射了无人探测器
Soviets managed to land unmanned probes.
他们一定是以某种方式得到了燃料棒
Somehow they must have picked up that fuel rod.
我们认为俄国人的推断出
We believe the Russians deduced
那只燃料棒是可裂变燃料装置
that the rod was a fissionable fuel assembly.
切尔诺贝利  苏联欧洲部分中西部城市
认为他们在切尔诺贝利对其监管及控制
Believed they had it mastered and harnessed it at Chernobyl.
我们接下来总共进行了六次任务
We went on six missions in all.
拍摄了大量照片和取样
We took hundreds of photos and samples.
最高机密
把它们永久性的封存起来
We locked them away forever.
而月球项目从此停止
And the moon program was shut down.
你们搜索地下室了吗
Well did you search the crash vault?
飞船的名字叫做方舟
The ships name was the Ark.
我目睹它从赛博坦逃走
I watched it escape Cybertron myself.
里面搭载着一项汽车人技术
It was carrying an Autobot
能让我们赢得战争
technology which would have won us the war.
里面还有机长
And its captain.
-机长是谁  -伟大的帮主  御天敌
- Who was this captain? - The Great Sentinel Prime.
发明这项技术的人
The technology's inventor.
他曾是汽车人的指挥官
He was commander of the Autobots.
是我的前任
Before me.
当务之急是
It's imperative that I find it
我必须在霸天虎知道具体位置之前找到它
before the Decepticons learn of its location.
我们汽车人的宇宙飞船可以到达那里
Our Autobot space craft has the ability to get there.
而你们只能祈祷这还来得及
And, you must pray it's in time.
我想见卡莉·斯宾塞
Hi, I'm here to see Carly Spenser.
卡莉
Carly!
你找到工作啦
You got the job?
-我自己都不敢相信  -真的找到工作啦
- This is crazy. - You really got it?
-对  -我说的对吧  多亏幸运兔
- Yes. - See what did I tell you, it's the bunny.
你就不用谢我了
You are so welcome.
-更喜欢我了吧  -一点点
- Do you like me a little more? - A little bit, yeah.
你说你是他的副馆长
You said you were his assistant curator,
你没说这家伙有座太空山
you didn't say the guy owns Space Mountain.
我知道  这里很美吧
I know, isn't it beautiful in here?
老板也酷毙了
And he's the coolest guy, ever.
-是吗  -没错
- Yeah. - Yeah.
山姆
Sam.
迪兰·古尔德
Dylan Gould.
见到你很高兴
Pleasure to meet you.
我也是
Pleasure meeting you.
卡莉常跟我提起你
Carly has told me a lot about you.
彼此彼此  你这栋房子真不错
Well, visa versa. It's a beautiful building you got.
简直就是星际迷航里的企业号
The Star Ship Enterprise here.
谢谢夸奖  这里漏雨
Thank you very much, it leaks.
在卡莉来帮忙整理藏品之前
Ah, before Carly came to help on the collection
这里一团糟
it was just a complete mess.
不过现在修复重回正轨了
But now the restorations are back on track.
今年我要再战圆石滩
I'm going to pebble beach this year,
再赢个奖杯放在那儿
going to need a trophy for that stand right there.
知道为什么吗
You know why?
因为你身边这位大美人儿
Because this woman right here,
正是我的秘密武器
...is my secret weapon.
你太夸张了
you exaggerate.
我只负责安排事宜而已
All I've done is get you organized.
你可远不止这样  管家婆
Oh you have done much more than that, my Dutchess.
昵称啊  挺有趣的
Nicknames, that's fun.
没错  管家婆
Yeah, the Dutchess.
她真可爱
She's adorable.
我从英国大使馆把她挖走的时候
You know when I stole her away from the British Embassy,
我说过  管理一个国家容易
I said, it's easy to manage a country.
管理无价的艺术藏品没那么简单
Try managing a priceless collection of art.
看这款1939年的德拉哈耶165敞篷车
Take a look at this 1939 Delahaye 165 Cabriolet.
法国人设计的
Designed by a French man.
看看这线条  真是精致无比
Look at the curves, elegant isn't it?
美极了
Beautiful.
让人充满欲望
Sensual.
让人想起女人的完美曲线
Built to evoke the body of the ideal woman.
快来
Come on.
我父亲有一张十块钱的桌子和一个梦想
My dad had a ten dollar desk and a dream.
由此他建立了一家大企业
And he built it into an empire.
我们是美国最大的会计师事务所
We're the largest accounting firm in the US.
我的商业投机是在他过世之后才开始的
I started off the adventure side after he passed.
未来就会如此
That's in the future.
在成功者身上下注
Try and bet on the winners.
收藏汽车让我保持清醒
See collecting cars helps me keep my sanity.
拍得不错
These look great.
那天真精彩  古尔德先生
Oh, that was a great day, Mr. Gould.
-我之前都没看到那张  -我也没见过
- I didn't see that one. - No, me either.
裤子够紧的
Jeans are tight.
来吧  来吧
Oh, here we go, here we go.
看见了吗
You see that?
以貌取人  看我开破车就看不起我
Judgment, judge a man by his car.
你还等着他看不起我吗
You going to wait on him while he's judging me?
你怎么啦  他是我老板
What's with you? He's my boss.
我们吃的住的花得都是他的钱
He still pays for our food, our rent.
不是  我完全理解
No, I totally understand.
我一点都不在乎  我明白  我被养活得不错
I'm totally fine, I get it. I'm well fed.
你猜怎么着  我不再当你的小白脸了
Guess what, I'm not your boy toy anymore.
现在起我提上裤子挣钱养家了
I got my big boy pants on now.
看见没
You see them?
麻烦上车  管家婆
In the car, thank you Duchess.
天哪  你吃他的醋吗
Oh, my god, are you threatened by him?
吃醋  我为什么吃醋
Threatened, what am I threatened by?
为他的钱  权  还是脸蛋儿吃醋
His money, his power, his good looks?
都不是  就选这个
None of the above, check!
你耍小孩子脾气的样子太性感了
Your temper tantrums are so sexy.
拜托上车吧
Get in the car, please.
山姆  向我谄媚的不是他一个
Sam, he's hardly the first man to ever smile at me.
我觉得我能处理好
I think I can handle it.
等等  是你对他的回应让我不爽
Hold on, hold on. It's..It's the smiling back part that gets me.
-知道吗  -不再对他笑了
- Okay. - No more smiles.
再也不笑了  我保证
Never again, I promise.
你看  我就吃这套
You see, that works for me.
别急  别急
Easy, easy.
这么弄可发动不起来
You're not going to get it started that way.
什么  我就是让它预热一下
What, I was just getting it ready.
我差不多做完了32%的修复工作
I'm about 32% done with my restoration.
镀上铬  在后面加个扰流板  搞定
Chrome work, put a spoiler on the back, done deal.
卡莉一直跟我说你为找不到工作烦心
You know Carly's been telling me you've been struggling job loss.
然后你都知道了
Just so you know.
我刚好是艾奇利塔系统董事会成员
I'm on the board for Accuretta systems.
我替你打了个电话
And I put in a call for you.
此事你知我知  好吗
Just keep it between us, okay.
她以你为荣
She's so proud of you.
你运气真好
You're a lucky man.
苍耳接近静海基地
Xanthium approaching Tranquility base.
这里是休斯顿  苍耳开始行动
Here's Houston, you're a go Xanthium.
阿姆斯特朗  祝你顺利
Armstrong, having a good day.
救护车  开始行动
Ratchet, let's roll.
他们把传感器打开了吗
Did they get that mag cap on?
联络已收到
Copy contact.
正在进入方舟
We're entering the Ark.
█
御天敌：汽车人前任首领
美洲豹6X6机场救援消防车
他的能量水平很低
His levels are faint.
█
救护车：汽车人成员
悍马越野车
Hummer.H2.SUV
把自己封藏了起来
Locked himself away.
来保护传送柱
To guard the pillars.
御天敌
Sentinel.
你要回家了  老朋友
You're coming home, old friend.
█
威震天：霸天虎首领
马克恐怖武装油罐车
Mack Fuel Truck
威震天万岁
All hail, Megatron.
主人来了  是主人
My master, it's master.
别那么贪心
Ah, don't be greedy.
我的小宝贝们
My fragile ones.
█
红蜘蛛：霸天虎成员
F-22 猛禽战斗机
您看起来不太好  主人
You look poor, Master.
见你如此羸弱让我何等心疼
How it pains me to see you so vulnerable, so weak.
省省你没用的漂亮话儿
Spare me you gaseous sycophant.
你知道我跟你说过什么  不许抵抗
You know what you were told. Resist nothing.
█
声波：霸天虎成员
奔驰 SLS AMG
声波来报告  威震天大人
Soundwave reporting, Lord Megatron.
你的小刺客有什么消息
And what news from your little assassin?
汽车人上钩了
Autobots have taken the bait.
他们发现了方舟
They discovered the Ark,
把里面的东西带回来了
and returned with its cargo.
干得好  跟踪去月球的飞船
You did me great honor, tracking that ship to the moon.
你的人类卧底没用了  声波
Your human collaborators have served their purpose, Soundwave.
是时候把清理废料了
It's time to eliminate loose ends.
激光鸟  把他们都杀了
Laserbeak, kill them all.
非常愿意
With pleasure.
你爸爸在家吗
Is your daddy home?
-然后马德琳说  -马德琳
- "Then Madeline said . . ." -Madeline!
你好  妈妈
Hello, mom.
从房子里滚出去
Get out of the house!
-你在我家干什么  -拜访一下而已
- What are you doing in my house? - Just visiting.
艾奇利塔系统
这么紧身暴露的还能算衣服吗
What's this hoochee-mama outfit?
是因为...
Just because...
不行  我们公司做的是航空工业
No. This is the aerospace baby.
我们这里不允许这样
We do not allow that here!
新人  看见没
New guy, you see that?
那个拉丁人这样太过分
That's a Latin melt down, okay.
要是你穿一身便装出现在我的办公室 你就被炒了
You ever show up in my office with a hoochie-mama outfit you're fired.
明白了吗
You got that, okay?
你要送信送上两年半
If you're going to be on this cart for 2 1/2 years, okay.
我要求你充满活力  爱岗敬业  有所成就
I want you to live it, love it and made it.
我的地盘没有靠关系升级这种事  这里纪律很严明
There's no ladder climbing in my office. I run a tight ship.
-是的  先生  -很好  去干活
- Yes, sir. - Okay, so move.
我找到了跟你提过的那份文件
I found that paper I was telling you about.
我们看什么呢
What are we looking at?
闭嘴
Shut up!
你再这么干我就揍死你
You do that to me again and I'll kick your ass.
-你好啊天使  -你好
- Hi Angel. - Hello.
你怎么样
You're good?
我要在市中心开个会  过来看你没问题吧
I had a meeting downtown, is it okay for me to stop by?
不知道  500页的员工守则
I don't know my 500 page
一下可看不完
employee conduct manual isn't exactly a page turner.
这不错
This is great
汽车人在外面拯救世界
Autobots are out there saving the world,
而我在整理四个活页夹子
and I organize four binders.
这可能是做梦吧  快来
It may be a dream, come on.
违反访客准则了
Visitor violation.
你没事吧
You okay?
绝对没有
Absolutely.
下一个该我
I'm next.
听着  星期六
Listen, Saturday.
有个工作上的聚会
There's a party at the house it's a work thing,
但是迪兰也邀请了你
but Dylan's invited you too.
是吗
Really, oh did he.
我想让你来给我捧场
I want you to come and laugh at my bad jokes.
你能来对我很重要  好吗
It would really mean a lot to me, okay.
我愿意去  你怎么过来的
I'd love to go. How did you get over here?
开车
A car.
你没有车
You don't have a car.
我有
Yes I do.
什么  你中彩票了吗
What, did you win it in a raffle?
他给了我一辆
Uh, he gave me one.
他给你一辆车吗
He gave you a car?
没错  我觉得是工作津贴
Yeah, I think it was a work perk.
工作津贴是吗
Hmm, a work perk.
他给你什么车
What kind of car did he gave you?
奔驰SLS AMG(霸天虎成员:声波)
Um, a Mercedes SLS AMG.
引擎很棒
Really throaty engine.
奔驰SLS AMG
Mercedes Benz SLS.
-性能也很好  -你开它过来的吗
- combines breathtaking performance... -You drove this here?
这是辆二十万美金的车
It's a $200,000 Car.
我知道
I know.
知道我要多久才能买得起这种车吗
You know how long it would take me to afford a car like this?
-很久  -是  差不多五十三年
- Long time. - Yeah like, 53 years.
他说这是送给我们两个人的
He said it was for both of us.
知道我们该怎么做吗  卖了它买座房子
You know what we should do? We should sell it and buy a house.
我知道你不开心
You're frustrated, I know.
我也曾这样
I've been there.
这叫有付出
It's called paying your dues.
就会有收获
Good things will happen.
女士们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen.
我要占用一点午餐时间整理好文件  都别走
I need some lunchtime filing done, stat.
谁想从布鲁斯·布拉索思那里得点分
Who would like to score some Bruce Brazos points?
布鲁斯  你找到要找的人了
Bruce, you found your guy.
威特维奇
Witwicky.
这家公司全靠他了
The man who makes this company run.
看看谁在这儿呢  是姐妹  非死不可的好友
Now who have we here, a sister, facebook friend?
还是推特上的推友呢
Twitter, tweeter.
-卡莉  这位是布鲁斯  布鲁斯  -您好
- Carly this is Bruce. Bruce. - Hi.
我是他女朋友  很高兴认识您
I'm his girlfriend, pleasure to meet you.
山姆说得没错  您的头发确实不错
Sam was right, you really do have smashing head of hair.
-谢谢夸奖  -不客气
- Well thank you. - Your welcome.
山姆  我得走了
Sam I gotta run.
给你  你的礼物
Here, your present.
你最喜欢的颜色
Your favorite color.
很高兴认识您  布拉索思先生
Nice to meet you Mr. Brazos.
我也是
And you.
再见啦
See ya boys.
我还因为夹子那事心烦呢  杰瑞
I'm still stewing about that binder incident, Jerry.
我喝完舒化奶再说行吗  托尼
May I finish my Chu Wah milk, Tony.
我才不关心你的外国奶
I don's care about your exotic milk.
我关心的是尊重
I care about respect.
我知道你是谁
I know who you are.
维奇  威特维奇
Wicky, Witwicky.
-我知道你  我在跟你说话  -让让
- You know who, I'm talking to you. - Excuse me.
谢谢
Thank you.
不不  慢点  小老虎
No, no, slow down tiger.
你在六张照片的背景中出现
You showed up on the background of six different photos.
在两个洲和外星人在一起
Two continents, with aliens.
在埃及的是你
That was you in Egypt.
对吧
Huh, right.
因为你认识那些外星人
Because you know the Aliens.
再见
See ya.
上衣还我
Give me my jacket.
我是王  深王
Hey, I am Wang, Deep Wang.
深王
Deep Wang.
你还没懂  是"深喉"的深
You're not getting it, "Deep Throat".
水门事件  我在和你对暗号
Watergate? I'm talking code to you...
他妈的
Damn it.
他们在监视监听
Shhh, they watch and listen.
我不能去政府部门
I can't go to the government.
你  你可以因为要出事了
You, you can because shit's going down.
Pink Floyd  英国乐队平克·佛洛依德  以迷幻与太空摇滚音乐赢得知名度
小伙子  这就是弗洛伊德的粉色代码
Son, it is code pink as in 'Floyd'.
月球阴暗面  你认为1972年后为何就没人上去过
Dark side, why do you think no ones been up there since 1972.
你说的是英语  很奇怪的英语
You speak in English, it's a very strange English.
因此
That's why un. Oh....oh.
不要  我要揍你了
Don't, I'm gonna hit ya.
那我会还击的  小伙子
Well I'm going to hit ya right back, son.
那是我的证据
That's my manifesto.
他们在清除我们
They are whacking us out.
所有知道阴影的人
Everyone who knows what is in the dark.
你的外星朋友有难
Your alien friends is in danger.
你知道谁是好人  随你怎么处置
You know the good ones, it's up to you.
慢点  山姆
Easy, Sam.
你看什么看
What are you looking at?
讨厌鬼
Yow, dog.
你看个蛋看
Did you look at my shit?
你是谁手下的
Who are you working for?
看看谁先眨眼
Stare down, you and me.
看来是我赢了
Guess I won.
月球卫星
Moons satelllites.
俄国空间项目
The Russian space program.
专家身亡
Experts dead.
太空计划结束
Space Program ends.
阴影
Dark side.
月之阴影
Dark side of the moon.
看我在洗手间门外发现什么了
Look what I found outside the bathroom, huh?
是你的吗  处理好
It yours? Deal with this.
是的  先生
Yes, sir.
你让我做的我都做了
I did everything you want.
我觉得我们真该谈谈
I really think we should talk,
因为有些东西...
because some of the stuff...
进来前先敲门
Whoa, knock first.
看不出来我很忙吗
Can't you see I'm busy.
你是谁  你是谁
Who are you, who are you?
你在厕所里跨坐在我身上
You straddled me in the stall.
这辈子只有过那么一次  我不会忘记的
That's happened to me once in this life, I wouldn't forget it.
-不不  -在厕所隔间
- No, no. - In the bathroom stall.
你把你的包裹拿了出来
You pulled your package out.
我们可不是情侣  好吗
Whoa, whoa, we are not boyfriends, okay.
我一个电话就可以让你下岗
One phone call from me and I'll have you fired.
我会这么干的  玻璃种
Oh yes I will, Gaylord.
你还好吗
You okay?
是痔疮犯了
It's a hemorrhoid.
我该待会儿再来吗  什么时候合适呢
Should I come back? When should I come back?
等你懂礼貌了再回来
Come back when you learn some manners.
我不认识他  我什么都不会说的
I don't know him, I would never say anything.
正像我许诺的一样
Okay, okay! I sabotaged the mapping satellite,
我破坏了绘图卫星
just like I promised.
我可以在程序里插入一个盲点作为额外附送
I can put a blind spot in the program as a bonus.
你还想让我怎么样
What more do you want from me?
杰瑞
Jerry.
我最喜欢你了
You are my favorite.
想我怎样我都会做的
I'll do whatever you want me to do.
我知道
I know.
我的上级让我...
My superiors need me to....
-什么  -让你自杀
- What? - Suicide you.
你跟威特维奇说了什么
What did you say to Witwicky?
靠
Shit.
想变成烤鸡吗  贱人
Huh, who want's some chicken dinner now, bitch?
因为今天你赶上王心情不好了
'Cause somebody messed with the wrong Wang today.
快点  你不是想要我吗
Come on, you want some of me.
我不想再被查克说教
I don't need anymore didactic lectures from Chuck.
天哪
Jesus!
报案
Get it legal.
那是杰瑞
That's Jerry.
行啦  各位  是的  一个同事死了
Come on, people. Yes, a workmate died.
但是往窗外看  他也不能死而复生
But looking out windows is not going to bring him back.
他以前就很压抑
The man was depressed.
不要拍照
Don't take a picture.
你可以一直看着他  但他不会站起来的
You can keep watching him but he's not getting up.
鸡蛋矮子是童谣中从墙上摔下跌得粉碎的蛋形矮胖子
你们都读过鸡蛋矮子
You all read Humpty Dumpty.
好了吧
Okay.
威特维奇
Witwicky.
我去应付媒体  你来打扫后方
I'm spearheading the press.  You clean up.
到处都是王的尸体
Wang is everywhere.
酒馆顶上  柱子上
He is in the bistro. He's in the bamboo.
栏杆上
He's on the balustrade.
你看见那里的人行道了吗
Did you see the sidewalk down there?
天呐
Oh, man.
把他私人物品装箱  停车位上的名字撤下来
Box up his personals, get his name off his parking space.
我们什么时候买了个新复印机
Hey, when did we get a new copier?
我看到的事情我绝不透露半个字
See, I'm not gonna say anything about what I saw?
你跟谁共用一个厕所完全是你的事
Who you share a toilet stall with is totally your business.
这绝对是日货
This is exceedingly Japanese.
日货总是这么难搞
They never make it easy.
你怎么了
What is with you?
这事很重要  卡莉
This is the really deal, Carly.
好吧  我要你保持镇静
Okay, I need you to stay composed.
是真的  我一会儿给你解释
It's real life, I'll explain to you later.
这是紧急情况  帮我联系兰诺克斯上校
We got an emergency, you gotta get Colonel Lennox in here.
跟霸天虎有关  霸天虎回来了
I'm reporting decepticons, the deceptions are back again.
-马上给我把那门打开  -冷静  先生
- You gotta open that gate up right now. - Easy, sir.
这里是卫生及公共服务部
This is health and human services.
好吧  都装备上M-4了
Right, packing M-4's?
M-4是卡宾枪的一种型号  用于部队实战
这么大阵势要保护什么  结肠袋吗
What are you protecting, colostomy bags?
-便盆还是止咳糖  -宝贝儿
- Bed pans, throat lozenges? - Babe.
你们的帽子哪里来的  护士学校吗
Where did you get that hat from? Nursing school?
所以你们是在保护护士跟足光粉吗
So your are nurses and foot powder protector.
-很好  不错  -宝贝儿  我觉得我们
- Oh, fantastic, yes. - Baby, I don't think we're in....
-找错地方了  -我们没有找错地方
- ... the right place. - We are in the right place.
我们没有找错地方
We are in the right place.
We are in the right place,
我马上要跟擎天柱说话
and I want to talk to Optimus right now.
你现在去给我找擎天柱
You're going to get me Optimus right now.
我想你找错地方了
I'm sure you got the wrong building.
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
霸天虎回来了  你听不懂吗
What part of the Deceptions are back don't you understand?
你能放聪明点吗
You're being a smart ass.
不要砸我的车  这可是收藏品
Do not hit my car, it's a collector's item.
要是我就不会这么干
I wouldn't do that.
你真是疯了
You're crazy.
检测到有能量块
We got an Energon reading.
车上有外星人
We've got aIiens in the vehicle!
你敢动就死定了  出来出来
You move, you're dead ! Out! Out!
车上有印度人
Got aliens in the vehicle!
-不许动  -我们不动
- Freeze! -Whoa, whoa, whoa, we're freezing.
你是不是...
Are you...
你耍我呢
Are you kidding me?
山姆  他们有枪
Sam, they've got guns!
-我抓住他了  快走  -大黄蜂
- I got him, go. - Bee!
大黄蜂在吗
Is Bee in there?
-好吧  你抓住我了  -趴下
- Okay, you got me. - Stay down.
你就是这么对待汽车人的
This how you treat Autobots?
我们是一条战线上的
We're on the same team.
好好享受你以后在7-11的工作吧  混球
Yeah, enjoy your next job at 7-11, dickhead.
-好吧  -混蛋
- That's right. - A-hole.
现在瞧瞧你的车吧
How's your car now?
那才是我的车
That's my car.
过来
Come here.
Come here!
别这样  山姆
Come on... Sam.
你怎么回事
What is your deal, huh?
我知道你们的什么秘密行动很重要
I know your black ops stuff is important.
要知道我不是想拦着你
You know I'm not trying to diminish it,
让你内疚或者怎么样的
or guilt trip you, or anything.
但是我好久没见到你了
But I just never see you anymore.
你就不能回来车库呆一个晚上吗
You can't come to the garage and just hang out one night?
山姆  你这么说我很难过
Sam, that makes me feel bad.
我真希望你难过  你就应该难过
Yeah, well, I hope you feel bad, you should feel bad.
看看我现在开的这个老破车
Look at the jalopy I'm driving now.
我每天都觉得很难过
I feel bad every single day.
跟我来  你们俩
Yo, let's go, both of you.
兰诺克斯要见你们
Lennox wants to see you.
怎么了  现在我们就配不上你了吗
What, we're not good enough for you anymore.
抱歉  宝贝儿  他们很粗鲁  对吗
Sorry, babe, they were very rude, right.
你给我把车修好
And you're fixing my car.
你反对吗
You don't think so?
要是你今天遇到了一个会飞的变态
Raise your hand if you had a
复印机忍者杀手  请举手
flying psycho ninja copier try to kill you today.
那些是我的铜指节
Those are my brass knuckles.
那是我脚环  需要我把那个也脱下来吗
That's my anklet, do I have to take that off too?
还有我脚趾环
And my toe rings?
全部鸟巢部队人员撤离本层
All NEST officials clear the floor.
距离接触行动  还有十分钟
We have ten minutes until attempted contact.
我们已经拿到
We've taken possession of
藏在御天敌飞船上的五个设备
the five devices that were hidden in the ship of Sentinel Prime.
某种程度上说他们是汽车人的原型科技
They're some kind of prototype Autobot technology.
他们说御天敌是他们文明里的爱因斯坦
They say Sentinel was the Einstein of his civilization.
所以我们要把这些锁起来
So we're going to keep these locked up,
直到我们弄清楚这些是什么
... until we know what we're dealing with.
现在不许任何人接近
Right now no one gets access.
-任何人  -今早有个姓王的认出我
- No one. - This Wang guy recognized me.
他让我来提醒你
He told me to warn you,
他说到月之阴影
he's talking about the dark side of the moon.
-然后他们把他杀了  -等一下  你说月亮
- Then they killed him. - Wait a minute, you mentioned the moon?
是啊  月之阴影
Yeah, dark side of the moon.
但是为什么霸天虎想要杀害人类呢
But why would the decepticons want to kill humans?
我以为他们的敌人是汽车人
I thought their war was with the Autobots.
这是他第一次做科学简报的时间
And that is when he made his first quick-look science report.
这就是我想要的
That's what I want..
那个女的是谁  好的
Who's the chick, okay.
请问  兰诺克斯上校
Excuse me, Colonel Lennox.
米樱局长
Director Mearing.
这位是山姆·威特维奇
This is Sam Witwicky.
-一个平民  -我知道他是谁  上校
- A civilian c.. - I know his name, Colonel.
我想知道谁让他进来的
I want to know who gave him clearance.
谁让我进来的  不如说是擎天柱
Who gave me Clearance? How about Optimus Prime.
在他降落在郊区寻找我房子的时候
When he touched down in suburbia looking for my house.
这位是国家情报局主管
This is the national intelligence director.
要是你...
In case you...
-你好  -藐视国家官员
- Hi. - Disrespecting a federal officer.
也许应该把你关起来  她是谁
Maybe that'll get you somewhere., who's she?
她是我女朋友
She's my girlfriend.
这算怎么回事  约会吗
What is this like a date?
她知道所有汽车人的事情
She knows all about the Autobots, okay.
她知道大黄蜂  而且她来自军人的家庭
She knows Bumblebee, and comes from a military family.
我可以替她担保
I can vouch for her.
我有一个主意
Hey, I have an idea.
不如我们说回那个重要的话题
How bout we get back to the important topics?
比如说我的脸差点被霸天虎切下来
Like the fact I almost had my face cut off by a Decepticon.
事实上  作为纳税人  我要投诉
As a tax payer I'd like to lodge a complaint as a matter of fact.
好了  听着
Okay, listen.
山姆公司的一个软件工程师今天被杀害了
One of the software engineers at Sam's office was murdered today.
他参与过航空航天局的月球绘图探测
He was involved in NASA's Lunar mapping probe.
事情是这样的  兰诺克斯上校
Here's the thing, Colonel Lennox.
我们不能把国家安全托付给年轻人
We cannot entrust national security to teenagers.
除非说有什么政策我不知道
Unless I missed the policy paper.
有吗
Are we doing that now?
没有  很好
No, good.
我不管你是谁
I don't care who you are.
要是你把在这里看到的说出去一个字
If you breathe a word of what you've seen here.
就以叛国罪把你扔进监狱
You will do time for treason.
明白了吗
Do you understand me?
我只听汽车人的命令
I'll take my orders from the Autobots.
我认识他们  我不认识你
I know them, I don't know you.
你会认识我的
You will.
御天敌
Sentinel Prime.
他貌似靠能量块维持生存  他已经用完了
He seems to run on Energon, and he's out of it.
他现在是在睡眠模式
He's in a sort of a sleep mode.
开始吧
Let us begin.
这就是伟大的领袖矩阵
It's the great matrix of leadership.
他掌握着宇宙中仅有的一样东西
He holds the only thing in the
能够重新启动变形金刚的火种
universe that can repower a Transformers spark.
太不可思议了
This is incredible.
御天敌
Sentinel Prime.
我们欢迎你回来
We bid you return.
复仇
Revenge.
-不  -不要开枪
- No. - Hold your fire.
-不要  御天敌  -不要开枪
- No, Sentinel. - Hold your fire.
是我  擎天柱
It is I, Optimus Prime.
没事了
It is all right.
你安全了
You are safe.
没什么好怕的
There's nothing to fear.
我们来了
We are here.
你回家了  御天敌
You are home, Sentinel.
战争
The war?
The war!
我们输了
The war was lost.
赛博坦现在已经成了不毛之地
Cybertron is now but a barren wasteland.
我们在地球避难
We have taken refuge here on Planet Earth.
人类是我们的盟军
Its human race is our allies.
我的飞船呢
My ship?
我们遭遇了袭击
We came under fire.
传送柱
The pillars.
传送柱在哪里
Where are the pillars?
你保住了五根
You saved five of them.
包括控制柱
Including the control pillar.
只有五根吗
Only five?
我们以前有上百根的
We once had hundreds.
打扰一下  先生们  我能问问
Excuse me, gentlemen. May I ask,
你们要寻找的科技是什么吗
what is this technology you're looking for?
它具有重塑宇宙的能力
It is the ability to reshape the universe.
集结所有传送柱就能形成空间桥
Together the pillars form a space bridge.
这是我设计的  只有我能控制
I designed and I alone can control it.
这打破了你们的物理学定理
It defied your laws of physics
物质一定要通过时间空间传输
to transport matter through time and space.
你们说的是瞬间传输  是吗
You're talking about a teleportation device, aren't you?
是的  传输资源和难民
Yes, for resources, for refuges.
难民  或者军队
Refuges or troops of soldiers.
武器  或者炮弹
Weapons, maybe bombs.
一种瞬间袭击的手段
A means of an instant strike,
这就是它的军事功能  对吗
that's its military function, isn't it?
这是我们的科技
It is our technology.
必须要归还给我们
And it must be returned.
是的  如果人类同意的话
Yes, if humans say so.
你不能把大规模杀伤武器
You can't just bring weapons
运到我们的地盘
of mass destruction into our atmosphere.
首先要申报海关
Kind of have to declare customs first.
经过叫做文书的小手续
A little formality called paperwork.
这是我们人类跟动物的区别
Kinda separates us from the animals.
如果你注意到我严肃的态度
I will overlook your condescending tone
我就忽略你这居高临下的语气
if you heave the gravity of mine.
绝不能让霸天虎知道空间桥在这里
The decepticons must never know the space bridge is here.
因为要是到了他们手上
For in their hands...
你们的世界就完蛋了
... it would mean the end of your world.
这文件做的太差
Totaly nightmare file.
那就展开调查吧
So the investigation is open.
我们会派特工去你办公室
We sent agents to your office.
现在
And for the time being,
我们会让汽车人护送你回家
we're going to send you home with Autobot protection.
我需要跟谁说
Wh.. Who do I need to speak to,
才能让你们明白我可以帮忙
to get you guys to understand I can help.
我可以帮忙
I can contribute.
我们都可以帮上忙  告诉我你知道什么
Hey, we can all help. You tell me what you know,
我可以跟你说说太阳系  和我去过所有有趣的星球
I could tell you about the solar system, all the fun pIanets to hang out in.
请从我桌子上下来
Get off my desk, please.
你掏枪了  好吧  那我帮不了你  她发火了
Aw, you pulling out guns. Okay, can't help you on that. She angry
天哪
Oh, my god.
你想要我怎么做  立刻回家
What do you envision for me? I go back home now?
回去上班  继续去复印吗  我是说...
I go back to work? I make copies? I mean...
这个部门里都是些有经验的
This is a unit for veteran
情报人员和特种部队
intelligence officers and special forces.
而不是开过特殊汽车的小男生
Not for boys who once owned special cars.
这么说有些刻薄吧  夫人
That's a bit harsh, isn't it ma'am?
不要叫我夫人  我不是夫人
Don't call me ma'am, I'm not a ma'am.
但你是女的  对吧
But you're a woman, aren't you?
那么...
Sooo.
那些是你的吗
Are those yours?
是的  中情局发的
Yeah, CIA.
我这么问只是因为我也有一个
I only ask because I also have a medal.
总统发的
From the President.
是的
Yeah.
不错  所以其实没那么复杂对吧
Great, so it's not that complicated, right?
没有我的批准  谁也不许跟汽车人一起工作
No one gets to work with the Autobots unless I approve it.
你是在破坏我的指挥系统
You're breaking my chain of command.
来吧  走吧
Come on, let's go.
你已经尽力了
You've done what you can for them.
请恕我直言  年轻人
With all due respect, young man.
我很欣赏你的所作所为
I appreciate what you did.
但是你不是战士
But you're not a soldier.
你是个送信的  你一直就是个送信的
You're a messenger, you've always been a messenger.
他是个英雄
He's a hero.
大黄蜂  你坐货物升降机  我们一会儿上面见
Bee, you take the freight elevator, I'll see you up there.
要开战了
Ah, this blows.
-那个女士把我们踢出局了  -是啊
- That lady officially kicked us out. - Yeah.
保护证人计划逊毙了
Witness protection program sucks.
是啊  但有大黄蜂和他的大炮
Yeah, but we're a whole
我们安全多了
lot safer with big yellow and his cannons.
那只狗什么都保护不了
That dog can't protect crap.
大黄蜂
Bee.
你怀念出去兜风的日子吗
You missing hang out.
是啊  我也是
Yeah, me too.
我真不敢相信她管我叫送信的
I don't believe she called me a messenger.
你能相信吗  我做了这么多  却只是个送信的
Do you believe that? After everything I've done, I'm a messenger.
我相信  跟你说  塞米  我们的感觉和你一样
Oh, I believe it. I tell ya, Sammy, we feel the same way.
地球上的人太无礼了
The disrespect on this rock is criminal.
我们得做点什么
We should do something about it.
大黄蜂
Bee.
我想知道他们为什么要杀害人类
I need to know why they're killing humans.
不如我们给专家打个电话
What say we call in the expert?
我下一位客人曾是美国情报人员
My next guest, is a former American intelligence operative
他曾勇敢说出
who has dared to speak out
我们的外星盟军实情
regarding our alleged military alliance,
而很多人称
... with what many describe
他们是外星球的雇佣兵
as a group of extraterrestrial mercenaries.
他是畅销书《代号英雄》的作者
He is the author of the best selling book, "Code-Name Hero".
有请我们的特工  西摩·西蒙斯
For our special agent, Seymour Simmons.
比尔  我是你的粉丝  我很高兴来到这里
Bill, big fan. Great to be here.
西蒙斯特工
Now, agent Simmons.
你希望我们相信这是我们
You would have us believe that it is in our best centuries
在外星内战中选择阵营的最好时机
to formally take sides in this so called alien civil war?
另一方想把我们砍了做早餐  所以
Well, the other side wanted to spank us for breakfast, so.
我不认为我们还有别的选择
I wouldn't exactly want to call it a toss up.
那些霸天虎们是很危险的
These decepticons are lethal.
但是民意调查显示有一半的人类
But polls show half the world
觉得所有的汽车人离开  地球才会安全
would feel safer with the Autobots completely gone.
把他们弄走
Get them out of here.
我们不需要他们
We don't need them here.
那我觉得睡觉的时候要拿个手榴弹才安全了
I feel safer when I sleep with a hand grenade.
我说的不一定对
It doesn't mean I'm always right.
谢谢  事实上  我们手里有文件显示你
Thank you. Here's a fact, we obtained documents that show you were
-已经被情报委员会开除了  -查克  我在做采访呢
- fired by the intelligence committee. - Chaz, I'm doing the interview.
是为了缩小规模  比尔  预算削减
Down sized. Bill, budget cuts.
-查克  闪一边去  -文件称你有严重妄想症的倾向
- Chaz, out. - ... report get severe delusional tendencies.
这是新闻陷阱
This is ambush journalism.
你想知道外星盟军的真相吗
You want the truth about the alien alliance?
来买我的书吧
Buy my book.
Buy my book!
趁现在还来得及  各位
Before it's to late, people.
比尔  你不服吗  脱光打一架
You want to a piece of me, Bill, you want get naked?
我随时奉陪  采访结束
I'm ready, interview is over.
-特工  你像发了疯  -你给我滚出去
- You sound like a pin-head agent. - You get out of my house.
我给你一个忠告吧
And I got a suggestion for you.
采访结束了  明白吗
It is over, understand?
损害防控
Damage control.
-管家  -很明显你弄得西蒙斯先生很心烦
- Dutch! - You have obviously upset Mr. Simmons.
给你23秒离开这间屋子
You have 23 seconds to leave the property.
我已经叫警察了
I have called the police.
你们是群不自量力的农民
You are peasant people throwing rocks at a giant.
接下来是什么  还有什么
What's up next, what have we got?
中午在市中心的新书签售会
Book signing midtown at noon,
然后是探索频道的真人秀节目
then your pitch reality show for discovery HM.
对了  还有这个
Oh, and I had this, um... um.
威特维奇  今天给我打了五个电话
The Witwicky who keeps calling me five times today.
那个孩子  他想做什么
The kid, what does he want?
我打电话是因为霸天虎回来了
I called because the decepticons
我想知道原因  我需要你的帮助
are back and I want to know why, and I need your help.
他们回来了
They're back?
那样的话  又能赚钱了
Well, that's good for business.
要是我告诉你我知道一个50年前
What if I told you I know a 50
外星秘密而没人告诉过你  怎么样
year old alien secret that nobody ever told you?
别诱惑我
Do not tempt my addiction.
我已经金盆洗手了  孩子
I have gone through withdrawal, kid.
管家  这条线路安全吗
Dutch, is this line secure?
不安全
No.
加密中...
别冒险
Don't take the risk.
我很有钱  还冒什么险
I'm rich, why should I?
别犯老毛病  我不会的
Do not relapse, I won't.
别让魔鬼们取得胜利
Do not let the demons win.
线路安全
好了
Got.
什么样的秘密
What kind of.... secret?
阿波罗号  月球  外星人  隐藏的
Apollo, moon, aliens, cover-up...
未来科技  暗杀  一类的东西
... future tech, assassinations, that kind of stuff.
阿波罗号
Oh, Apollo.
管家
Dutch!
告诉威震天  跟哥跳个舞吧
Tell Megatron, let's tango.
这个星球如此宏伟  如此宁静
So majestic and peaceful, this planet.
一点都不像赛博坦的末日岁月
Unlike the final days of Cybertron.
我很想知道它本来会是什么样子
I've wondered what might have been.
如果是你指挥了最后的战斗
If you had fought the final battle.
而不是我
Instead of me.
永远不要为过去悲伤  年轻的战士
Never morn the past, young warrior.
正是因为你  我们的种族才得以存续
Thanks to you, our race survives.
你曾是我们的首领  御天敌
You were our leader, Sentinel.
再次领导我们是你的权利
It is your right to lead us again.
在一个我不了解的世界
In a world I do not know.
我不再是你的老师了  擎天柱
I am no longer your teacher, Optimus.
现在你是我的老师
You are mine.
你得查清楚这件事
You've got to break this case down.
这些宇航员的死亡迅速蔓延
What we have here is an astronaut epidemic.
战争中失踪的  去世了的  交通事故的
M.I.A., dead, died in a car accident,
被谋杀的  送医时死亡的  车祸死的
killed, D.O.A., car death.
就像是这些家伙不会开车
It's like these guys can't drive.
他们可以飞去外太空
They can fly into outer space.
但是他们却不会开汽车
But they can't drive a car.
你的资料拿到了  威特维奇
Procured your information, Witwicky.
谢谢你  布鲁斯
Thank you, Bruce.
别关门
Noo.
你得让我见识一下  就一下
You let me see one of them, one time.
-快点  -很快的
- Quick. - Very.
这是勘测命令
Here's their reconnaissance order.
上面说航天航空局2009年启动
It say's NASA launched in 2009.
看  记录显示王可能弄乱了代码
See, forensics show Wang may have messed with the code
以阻止他们对月球的远端进行绘图
preventing it from mapping the far side of the moon
也就是阴影一面
which is also the dark side.
真特么了不起
Freaking awesome.
他们跟我们交易  恐吓我们
They pay for trade us, intimidate us.
强迫我们干些不法勾当
... coerce us to do their dirty work.
一旦他们完成了
And once they're done?
咔嚓
Dushhhh.
就杀人灭口
The double tap cerebellum.
所以这些人是在替霸天虎效力
So humans are working for the Decepticons.
我觉得这跟霸天虎
I don't think this is about the Decepticons.
在找月球上的什么东西没关系
looking for something on the moon.
我想是他们是想隐藏什么
I think it's about something they wanted to hide.
跟老爸过两招
Come to daddy.
来吧  放马过来
Come on, throw down.
你小时候生病吃错药了吧
Did you eat a lot of paint chips when you were a kid?
真是个怪胎
The freak.
喜欢吗
Hah, like it.
我怕痒
I'm ticklish...
先生
Sir.
这里正在举行一个高层的外星情报会议
Having a pretty high level alien Intel confab here.
你还不够资格出现在这里吧
That I don't think you're cleared for.
-跑腿的  -是的  你是对的
- Errand boy. - Yeah, you're right.
-这机器人真给力  -布鲁斯  你该走了
- It's a bitchin' robot. - I think it's time to go, Bruce, okay?
谢谢你让我进来
Thank you so much for this.
还是快走吧  布鲁斯
Better go, Bruce.
我都要冒烟了
Hey, I'm smokin' over here.
下载失踪的俄罗斯宇航员资料
Downloading missing Russian cosmonauts.
苏联取消过一次载人登月任务
Turns out the soviets cancelled a manned mission to the moon.
是在1972年
The moon, in 1972
当时有2名苏联宇航员隐匿在美国
when 2 of cosmonauts went into hiding in America.
我刚找到他们了
And I just found them, aaaah.
你真是个天才  里恩
You're a genius, Brains.
这招真行  大黄蜂
Oh, that was smooth, Bumble Bee.
差了一大截
Missed it by that much.
你好
Hi.
有人告诉我怎么了吗
Would somebody tell me what the hell's going on?
你是谁
Who are you?
-你是谁  -我是谁
- Who are you? - Who am I?
那是谁  管家  搜她身
Who is that? Dutch, frisk her.
-当然  -不要
- Certainly. - Here, no.
管家
Dutch, um...
别碰我
Don't touch me.
-我不碰她  -山姆
- I'm not going to touch her. - Sam?
天使
Angel.
我在工作
Uh, I was working.
对于这一切  我很抱歉
I'm sorry about this.
很好  我们无家可归了
Great, we're homeless.
她住这里吗
She lives here?
你有机会搜她身
You had your chance to frisk her.
我有女朋友
I have a girl friend.
是吗  叫什么
Really, what's her name?
印蒂亚
Innn...dia.
我们说好要去参加迪兰的聚会  记得吗
We're suppose to be at Dylan's party, remember?
没忘  可你也知道  我那些朋友
I do remember, but you know, my friends,
需要我  现在走不开
...they need me. I have to be here right now.
还有什么  汽车人以及军方
And what, the Autobots and the
他们无法独自搞定此事
military they can't handle this on their own.
知道我喜欢你那些战争故事什么吗  山姆
You know what I liked about your war stories, Sam?
因为它们只是故事
It's that they were stories.
都是些过去的事情
They were in the past.
听着  我知道你想起了你哥哥
Look, I know you're thinking about your brother.
还有你的家人
Okay, and you're thinking about your family.
但这次情况不一样
And it's not that situation.
-不一样吗  -不一样
- No? - No.
怎么不一样
Why not?
怎么就不一样呢  山姆
Why isn't it, Sam?
你觉得我们是想让我哥哥活着  还是想要奖章
You think we'd rather has his medals, or we'd rather have him?
我知道  我明白
I hear you, I get it.
你拿我的兔子去哪儿  站住
Where are you taking my bunny, stop.
就等一下
Just stop for a second.
你以为昨晚上我睡着了吗
You think I could sleep last night?
我终于明白  山姆想冒险
And then it hit me. No, Sam want's to be in danger.
没有冒险就活不下去
He doesn't know who he is without it.
我只想有人需要我
I just wanna matter.
我需要你
You matter to me.
我知道你是担心我  我知道
I know you're worried, I know you're worried.
但我向你保证  我可以搞定
But I promise you I can, I can handle this.
能行吗  你能保证吗
Can you, you can promise it?
我保证
I promise.
山姆  我不想失去你  我知道这件事情的后果
Sam, I don't want to loose you, and I know where this leads.
我还没准备好
I'm not ready for this.
你和我一起去吗
Are you coming with me?
我办不到
I can't.
好吧
Okay.
给你的脚
Here's your foot.
真正的勇士得直面路途上的孤独
A warrior's path is a solitary one.
她怎么买得起这样的车
How the hell does she afford that car?
-她老板送的  -有钱的混蛋
- Her boss. - Rich bastards.
我以前恨死这些家伙了
I used to hate them.
但现在...
But now it's...
骑上快马去追捕两名俄罗斯宇航员
Going to a gig on a hunt for two Russian Cosmonauts.
没有什么比开着迈巴赫更爽的了  是吧
Nothing like driving in a Maybach, huh?
告诉你  只有德国人真正懂车
Germans know how to make cars, let me tell ya.
我这个管家  前国家安全局成员
My Dutch man. Former NSA,
网络特别探员
Cyber sleuth extraordinaire.
一路跟踪他们至此
Tracked them down, here.
这么说这些宇航员想藏起来  为什么呢
So these cosmonauts wanted to hide. Why?
我看到一个目标
Bingo, I got a match.
你简直是只德国牧羊犬  管家
You're a German Shepard, Dutch.
俄罗斯人
The thing about Russians is...
都不喜言谈
...they never like to talk.
得用点全球通用语言
It's going to take a little of the international language.
-Dos vedanya  -这是再见的意思
- Dos vedanya. - That means goodbye.
谁来引领革命
Who's to get revolution.
一个名人  不知道叫什么
A famous, I have no idea.
管家
Dutch.
来点狠话
Give me something tough.
-Baryshnikov  -我们会说英语
- Baryshnikov. - We do speak English.
管家  你真没用
Dutch, you suck.
这是斯拉夫字母
It's a Cyrillic, alphabet.
就像些计算器上你来从来用不到的按键
It's like all the buttons you never push on a calculator.
不是我没用
I don't suck.
西摩·西蒙斯特工  隶属第八区  前第七区
Agent Seymour Simmons, Sector Eight , formerly Seven
我们知道你的来历
We know who you are.
宇航员
Cosmonaut chicks.
那又怎样
So what?
你本应航行到月球的阴影  然而
You were suppose to travel to the Dark side of the moon, then....
忽然一切都取消了
It all got shut down.
问题是
The question is.
为什么
Why?
我的孩子可以在这吸烟吗
Can my child smoke in here?
好吧  没事  好吧
Okay, all right. Okay!
-开枪啊  -这个菜鸟是谁
- Yeah, shoot me. - Who was this delish, huh?
我愿意为国捐躯  你呢
I'm wiIling to die for my country.  Are you?
是吗
ReaIly?
你真漂亮
You are beautiful.
没人说你很漂亮吗
Has anyone told you, you're beautiful?
因为她就是个美人
'Cause she's a beautiful woman.
管家  回笼子里
Dutch, back in the cage.
让你的伙计别乱来  求求你稳住他
Control your boy, please control your boy.
管家  住手
Dutch, stop!
抱歉  这是老毛病
I'm so sorry. That is the old me.
好了  大家都冷静下来
Okay, let's everybody just calm down.
让我们降降温  把枪放下  放松点
Let's lower the heat, lower the guns. Just relax.
第二次世界大战结束了
World War 2 is over.
你将看到的是前苏联最高机密之一
You're about to see one of the biggest soviet secrets.
是美国人首次将人类送上月球
America first to send men to the moon.
但首次将摄像机送上去的是前苏联
But U.S.S.R. First to send camera.
1959年  我们的月球三号
In 1959 our Lunar 3.
拍下了月球阴影  背光的那一侧
take picture of the Dark, the shadow side.
什么都没看到
See's nothing.
-可是在1963年  月球四号看到  -奇怪的岩石
- But in 1963 Lunar 4 sees.. - ... strange rocks.
-是的  -遍布在飞船周围
- Yeah. - Around the ship.
数以百计
Hundreds of them.
给  这是照片
Here, show picture.
有一些拖痕
With some, drag marks.
我看过  这些不是岩石
I've seen these, these aren't rocks.
这些是传送柱
These are pillars.
外星人用来搭建太空桥的传送柱
Alien pillars for a space bridge.
因为汽车人也有五个  所以我们知道
We know about them because the Autobots have five of these.
霸天虎们肯定在阿波罗11到达之前
The decepticons must have
袭击了飞船
raided the ship before Apollo 11 ever got there.
拿走传送柱藏了起来
Took the pillars and hid them.
这个说不通  霸天虎攻击了飞船
Well that doesn't make sense. The Decepticons have the ship.
所有能量柱都归他们了
They have all those pillars.
如果说只有御天敌才能使用
Why would they leave Sentinel...
他们为什么留下他
... of these if he's the only one that can use them?
除非
Unless...
他们仍然需要他
He's the one thing they still need.
我们得和御天敌会面
We got to meet up with Sentinel.
跟他会合  并保证他的安全
Rendezvous with him, and keep him safe.
米樱  我刚带上御天敌  擎天柱十分钟后到
Mearing, I just picked up Sentinel, Optimus is 10 minutes behind.
我们正赶往鸟巢基地
We're coming in NEST, now.
威特维奇先生  我想我已经讲清楚了
Mr. Witwicky I thought I made it clear to you,
不要打这个电话
that I did not want you calling this phone.
听着  整件事情从一开始就是个阴谋
Listen, the whole thing has been a set up since the beginning.
霸天虎想利用擎天柱找到御天敌
Decepticons wanted Optimus to find Sentinel,
因为只有擎天柱才能让他复活
because only Optimus could revive him.
可是我们掌握着太空桥
But we have the space bridge.
米樱  你只不过有五个传送柱而已
Mearing, you have five pillars.
我刚刚得知他们有上百个
I just learned that they have hundreds.
你被利用了
You're doing exactly what they wanted you to do.
听着
What do I need to say to you.
霸天虎为御天敌而来
The Decepticons are coming for Sentinel Prime.
立刻赶往鸟巢基地
We're going to NEST.
收到能量警报
We have an Energon alert.
在特区干道检测到能量
Energon readings detected on the D. C. parkway.
目前跟踪到三辆越野车
Currently tracking three black Suburban.
█
恐惧战队：霸天虎成员
（曲轴箱 短柄斧 撬棍）
雪佛兰 Sburban SUV
大黄蜂  你得把御天敌带出去  你得保护他
B, you gotta get Sentinel out of here, you got to guard him.
天啊  我要被炒了
Oh mein gott, oh I'm fired.
小心点  小心点
Watch out, watch out.
逮着了
Gotcha.
开枪  开枪
Shoot him, shoot him!
快开枪  大黄蜂
Shoot him, B.
大黄蜂  快跑  再快点  再快点  大黄蜂  跑
B, you gotta move. Faster, faster B, go!
完了
Wipeout.
好了  返回鸟巢基地
Come on, back to NEST.
█
横炮：汽车人成员
考维特黄貂鱼百年概念跑车
意大利人  我来追他
Dino, I got him.
铁皮
Ironhide!
有问题吗
Is there a problem?
陷入小小的僵局
Whoa, little Mexican stand-off we got here.
放下武器
Weapons down.
这样我们会让你们有尊严地逃跑
And we'll let you escape with your dignity.
放下武器
Drop them.
很好
That's good.
铁皮  当心
Ironhide, watch out.
铁皮  拿着
Ironhide, catch.
小心后面
Behind you.
无耻霸天虎
Decepticon punk.
解决
Class dismissed.
-里面  我们走  -快
- Inside, let's go. - Move.
快  快走
Quick, move it.
-兰诺克斯  -走  走  走  走
- Lennox. - Go, go, go, go.
到处都是霸天虎
We got decepticons everywhere.
我已经出动全部人马出去找了
I got my whole team deployed looking for them.
铁皮
Ironhide!
保护好御天敌  把他锁在里面
Protect Sentinel, get him locked up inside.
包在我身上
Consider it done.
你的任务是守护好他  他是整件事情的核心
You gotta guard him, because he's the key to the whole thing.
确实如此
Indeed I am.
你必须意识到的是  我亲爱的汽车人兄弟
What you must realized, my Autobot brothers.
我们永远也不可能赢得这场战争
Is we were never going to win the war.
为我们星球的存亡着想
For the sake of our planets survival.
必须同威震天
A deal had to be made.
妥协
With Megatron.
退后
Get back!
你做了什么
What have you done?
据此  我解除你的职权
I hereby discharge you from duty.
-大黄蜂  -退后
- B! - Get back.
把所有鸟巢部队召回到基地
Rally all the NEST forces back to the base.
来吧  快走
Come on, move.
不
No. . .
找个医生来  我们这里人手不够
Get a medic down here! We don't have enough men.
别招惹御天敌
Do not engage Sentinel.
去后门
Just go to the back gate.
隐蔽
Take cover!
小心左侧  小心左侧
Watch left! Watch left!
走  跟上
Go, follow me.
开火
Start firing.
-指挥官  别去那边  -退下
- Director, don't go there! - Stand down!
御天敌
Hey, Sentinel.
怎么了
What is going on?
你在干什么
What do you think you're doing?
我是帮主
I am a Prime.
无须听从你的命令
I do not take orders from you.
米樱指挥官快走  我们不是他的对手  快走
Director Mearing come on. We can't fight him, let's go.
-我们得走  -立刻
- We have to go. - Now.
把属于我的还给我
Return what belongs to me.
天啊
Oh, my god.
-大家都好吗  -所有人都出来了吗
- You guys okay?  - Is everybody out?
大家保持冷静  你们不会有事
Everybody stay calm. You're gonna be fine
看看  擎天柱
Yeah take a look, Optimus.
这都是因你而起
This is all on you.
御天敌攻击了地下室
The Sentinel hit the vault.
把传送柱带走了
Took the pillars.
快来  我们走
Come on, let's go.
这样  通知101伞兵部队
All right, notify the 101st airborne.
我们得把东西追回来
We need to hunt this thing down.
卡莉
Carly.
篝火弄的  热乎乎的
Hot from a little camp fire.
曲奇饼
Smores.
不错吧  我们真的生活在世外
Isn't this great, we are really living off the land.
爸  妈  有没看到卡莉回来过啊
Ma, Dad. Have you guys seen Carly come home yet?
不好意思  你能先敲门吗
Excuse me, can you knock please.
这是我们的卧室
This is our bedroom.
她为什么不在家呢
Why wouldn't she be at home?
我们吵架了  而且
We had a fight, and....
我们可能已经分手了  或者正要分手
We might have broken up, or be on a break.
我也搞不清
I don't really know.
-什么  -听着  我没法谈这个
- What!?.. Noo. - Look, I can't talk about it.
你开玩笑吧
You gotta be kidding me.
我现在没功夫跟你谈论细节  妈  我得找到她
I can't go into details now, Mom. I have to find her.
山姆  我们得开个家庭会议
Sam, we're having a family meeting.
家庭会议
Family meeting.
你可能还不知道  不过你爸爸和我
You may not know this. But your
并不是一直以来都这么愉快地相处
father and I were not always this perfectly happy.
你知道在我们的婚姻中我也曾想过
You know there was a time in our marriage when I thought,
这次过不下去了
"This is not going to work out."
-你可以快点吗  -我只是希望你
- Can you please hurry up. - I'm just hope you ...
-能够明白  -她会毁了他
- .. just understand that you... - She's damaging him.
你是和世界头号大美女分手
...break up with one world class hottie.
-不  停  停  够了  -嗯
- No, stop, stop, okay. - Yeah.
她甩了我  我就找个更好的
She dumped me, I moved to something better.
没错  我更高兴了
That's it, I'm a happier person.
这是第二个美女  而你要失去她了
The second beautiful girl, and you lose her.
你怎么不帮我
Why don't you help me?
-他们只是吵架了  -是打架了
- They had an argument. - We had a fight.
好吧  可是你找不到第三个了
Okay, but you're not going to get a third one.
除非你有个大...
I mean unless you have like a big...
什么  妈妈
What the, mom!
妈  妈  我不想谈这个了
Mom, mom, don't want to talk about it.
也许你只是不知道怎么做
Maybe you just don't know what you are doing
-只是不想谈  -你需要本书
- Just don't want to talk. - You need a book.
跟她说你永远都是错的
You'll always wrong.
-习惯就好了  -好的  这就是你要读的
- Get used to it. -Okay, this you gotta read this.
书名叫《女士优先》  里面有些
She comes first, there's some killer...
-确实不错的东西  -别  别  别
- ...shit in here. - No, No, No.
-看看吧  -免谈  免谈
- Ah, let's get this. - No, no.
-不  不  -坐下  坐下
- No, no. - Sit down. Sit down!
支持我
Back me up.
有快乐的妻子  就有幸福的生活
Happy wife, happy life.
-没错  -不快乐的妻子
- Yeah. - unhappy wife
将会使得你的下半辈子惨不忍睹
Stone cold misery for the rest of your...
-够了  -这是事实
- Stop. - It's true.
我只是想说
All I'm saying is.
你爱这个女孩吗
Do you love this girl?
她就是我要找的
She's the one.
那么你就得想法得到她
Then you gotta go get her.
我是说  你爸爸和我闹矛盾的时候
I mean, your dad and I, when we had troubles.
即便天涯海角他也会找到我
He moved heaven and earth to find me.
不是吗  告诉他你怎么说的
Would he, say what you said.
说啊
Say it.
我会伴你左右  直到天荒地老
I would follow you to the end of time.
-是不是挺傻冒的  -不
- Does that suck or what? - No.
-就像一部烂科幻电影  -不  很温馨
- It's like a bad sci-fi film. - No. It is so sweet.
我要你们离开这里
I want you to get out of the city.
越远越好
I want you guys to get as far away from here as you can.
明白吗
You understand?
我爱你们
I love you.
哦  主人
Oh, my master.
您的计划实在高明
Such a brilliant scheme.
那么  御天敌离开赛博坦的时候
So, when Sentinel left Cybertron,
就是要叛变
...it was to defect.
在命运将我们都打败之前
He was meant to rendezvous with me here on Earth,
他本该和我在地球会合
before fate waylaid us both.
能让他复活的唯一办法
The only way to revive him,
就是擎天柱和矩阵
...we needed Prime and his matrix.
天衣无缝的策略
Excellent strategy.
我的  我的
Mine, mine!
所以他现在是您的伙伴了  主人
So he is now your partner, master.
拉拢到他是我最大的胜利
He is my greatest triumph.
真是叹为观止
So impressive.
开始传送
Commencing transport.
住手  不  不  不  御天敌
Stop! No, no, no Sentinel!
原谅我
Forgive me.
我们就在这
Here we are.
来打吧
Fight us now.
遇敌
Contact!
小心  快躲
Watch out! Move it! Move it!
汽车人  撤退
Autobots, retreat.
为什么  御天敌  为什么
Why Sentinel, why?
为了赛博坦
For Cybertron.
为了我们的家
For our home.
战争毁掉的东西  我们可以重建
What war destroyed, we can rebuild.
但要与霸天虎联合才有可能
But only if we join with the Decepticons.
不  不是非这样不可
No, it's not the only way.
这里才是我们的家
This is our home.
我们必须保护人类
We must defend the humans.
你大错特错  擎天柱
So lost you are, Optimus.
在赛博坦我们是上帝
On Cybertron we were Gods.
而这里他们却叫我们机器
And here they call us machines.
让人类做我们的奴隶
Let the humans serve us.
或者毁灭
Or perish.
你该庆幸我没杀你
You're lucky I didn't kill you.
过不了多久  你就会明白的
In time, you'll see.
这事没完
It's not over.
如果我是他
And if I were him,
我会半刻也不让你脱离我的视线范围
...I wouldn't let you out of my sight for one second.
真是好笑  一路以来我都在想
It's funny I was just thinking on the way over here,
也许我该听听迪兰的意见
I really could use some advice from Dylan.
-他还真有意见  可以跟你谈谈吗  -欢迎光临
- And there he is. Can I speak to you? - Welcome.
请坐  喝点东西吧
Please sit down, have a drink.
知道吗  我不需要饮料
You know what, I don't need a drink.
或车  或工作
Or a car, or a job.
我只想单独跟我女朋友谈谈
I just need to speak to my girlfriend alone.
没什么问题吧  灯泡先生
Is that okay with you, Mr. Inappropriate?
失陪
Excuse me.
-怎么回事  -到外面告诉你
- What's going on? - I'll tell you outside.
我真觉得可以帮到你  山姆
I really think I can help you, Sam.
我还记得跟父亲的谈到艰难的选择
I remember a talk I had with my dad once, about tough choices.
现在不是时候  我有些事需要处理
Now's not the time, I'll set something up, though.
那还要回溯到我爸爸的公司
'Cause that was way back when my dad's firm was in charge
负责航空航天局的预算审核及报账工作
of budget review and accounting for NASA.
他教会我的事情是
You see the thing that he taught me was...
战争本身与你无关时
When it's not your war,
要跟胜利的一方联手
you join the side that's going to win.
太直接了吗  还是我不讨人喜欢
Too direct, or was it just me?
显然责任不在您  先生
Certainly not you, sir.
你是我的
You're mine.
-帮忙  谁能帮帮忙  -山姆  我出不去
- Get help. Someone get help. - Sam, I can't get out.
-晚安  -晚安  迪兰先生
- Goodnight - Goodnight Mr. Dylan.
山姆  救我出去
Sam, get me out of here.
救命
Help.
Get help.
他还年轻  会懂事的
He's young, he will learn.
-让我出去  -晚安
- Get me out. - Goodnight.
今晚很愉快
This was a fun night.
你真以为自己是第一个
You really think you're the
被要求介入一场宏大的外星人事件中吗
first man ever asked to join a noble alien cause?
你是谁
Who are you?
知道为什么自1972年后
You know why we've not
我们没再重返月球吗
been back to the moon since 1972?
因为这两个家伙
Because these two.
他们来找我爸
They came to my dad and
让他在账目中做些手脚
they told him to do some creative accounting.
使得返回月球花费太高
Make it way to expensive to ever go back.
所以他和其他人
So he and others, shut
终止了美俄两国的太空计划
down the American and Russian space programs.
而且自那以后他们就是我们的客户了
And they've been our clients ever since.
你还帮忙杀人吗
You helped to kill people?
有得选吗
You think they give you a choice?
此外  我也不是直接参与其中
Besides, it's not like I personally participated.
我是个联络员
I am a liaison.
负责联络
I liaise.
这样浪费时间就太没诚意了  山姆
It's hostile take over time, Sam.
山姆
Sam!
让她走
Let her go.
山姆
Sam.
我监视你好多年了  山姆
I've had my eye on you for years, Sam.
再也找不到比你更好的
You're the one spy I've never been
能够安排在汽车人身边的间谍了
able to provide as the one close to the Autobots.
山姆  别听他的
Sam, don't do what he wants.
不  他会的
Yes he will.
像他们一样
They all do.
他们会宰了她  懂吗
They will slaughter her. You understand me.
你眨眼的功夫
The time it takes you to blink,
他们就会干掉她  也会干掉我
they will do it to her, and they will do it to me.
所以当别人给你工作时
So you show a little respect.
得有起码的尊重
When someone offers you a job.
手腕
Wrist.
你要去跟踪擎天柱
You are to track down, Optimus Prime.
人类之中他只信任你
Because you're the one human he trusts.
你去问他
You will ask one question.
他打算如何反击
How does he intend to fight back?
策略  战术  所有的东西
Strategies, tactics, everything.
像被咬了一口  是吧
Has a nasty little bite, doesn't it.
高科技产品
It's very high tech.
通过它  我们可以知道
It lets us see
你看到了什么  听到了什么
what you see, hear what you hear.
而且它可以入侵你的神经系统
And it attacks your nervous system.
所以别玩花招
So if you so much as try and signal.
我不知道还要告诉你什么  山姆
I don't know what to tell you, Sam.
关系产生结果
Relationships have consequences.
我在这里是因为我父亲
I am here because my father,
她在这里则是因为你
she is here because of you.
别  别  别  别
Stop! Stop, stop...stop.
声波  暂且别动她
Soundwave, if you please.
山姆
Sam.
完成你的任务
Do your job.
她就没事  我向你保证
She'll be safe. I give you my word.
我会宰了你
I'll kill you.
给我记住
You have my word.
全体战斗员进入一级备战
Combatant commands are now at Defcon 1.
大约有两百个霸天虎藏在暗处
Approximately 200 Decepticons are in hiding.
南美和中国
Energon detectors have been
能量检测设备都被触发
triggered as far away as South America and China.
联合国刚刚收到一份加密音频文件
The U.N. just received an encrypted audio file.
说是来自汽车人的领导者
They say it's from the leaders of the Autobots.
地球的守卫者们
Defenders of Earth.
我们为你们的自然资源而来
We have come for your natural resources.
以此重建我们受损的星球
To rebuild our damaged planet.
当运完所有我们需要的东西
When we have transported all we needed.
就会还你们和平
We will leave your world in peace.
要想获得这种和平
For such peace to exist.
必须立刻驱逐你们庇护的所有汽车人叛徒
You must immediately exile the Autobot rebels you have harbored.
无商量余地
Non negotiable.
请与叛逆者断绝关系
Renounce the rebels.
等候你们的答复
We await your reply.
我们在中转站听你的汇报
We'll debrief you in transit.
我不知道我对你们有何帮助
Yeah I really don't see how I can be of any help.
你们个个都很忙
I mean you guys seem pretty busy.
我们可再约时间
We can just do this another time, I think.
每次我都低估了你
I have underestimated you at every turn.
你  什么
You..Ha...what?
你提醒过我们说他们在利用人类
You warned us that they were using humans.
而且你知道御天敌是关键
And you knew that Sentinel was the key.
长官
Director.
我算老几  你才是专家
Oh, who am I? Hey, you're the expert.
我只是一个四处走动的危险人物
I'm just a walking security risk.
你没事吧
Are you all right?
没事
Yes.
-不  你有事  看都在冒汗了  -没事  真没事
- No you're not, you're sweating. - No, I'm fine.
没事  我冒汗是因为我紧张
I'm fine. I'm sweating because I'm nervous.
我紧张是因为
I'm nervous because you
你告诉我这样的秘密
got me in here for this information, okay.
我是个微博控  什么东西都往上写
I'm a twitter junkie, I blog everything,
不能保守秘密
I can't keep secrets.
-你不敢  -我在跟你说实话
- Oh you wouldn't dare. - That's the truth, I'm telling you.
你不敢
You wouldn't dare.
长官  十五号线有你的电话
Director I got a call for you at 15.
你在干嘛
What are you doing?
没干嘛  你在干嘛
Nothing, what are you doing?
离我远点
Get away from me.
今天在首都发生了一些列重要事件
It's been a remarkable series of events today at the Capitol.
片刻之前  立法会
Just moments ago legislation was
通过了驱逐美国领土上汽车人的法案
passed to exile the Autobots from American shores.
美国军队同他们的联盟正式结束
The U.S. Military alliance with them is officially over.
-来自白宫的消息和  -是
- The words of the house and the... - Yeah.
当局领导还有此次决议的支持者
..Authority leaders the sponsor of today's resolution.
-什么  -我们不能故意邀请
- What? - We cannot in good conscious invite...
他们不能这样做  你得告诉他们不能这样做
They can't do this, you gotta tell them they can't do that.
好  这是官方决定  大家开始行动
Okay, it's official, it's a go people!
他们是我们的盟军
These are our allies.
汽车人为我们而战  跟我们并肩作战
The Autobot's fought for us, they fought with us.
但我们现在什么处境呢
And where are we now?
面对着敌人的入侵
Facing an enemy invasion.
面对着贪得无厌的敌人
With an enemy that has the means to deploy countless more.
你还知道什么吗
If there's more you know?
任何关于敌人意图的消息
Anything at all about the enemies intentions.
现在要告诉我们了
Now's the time to tell.
汽车人没法离开这个星球
Autobots have no way of leaving this planet.
这一点你就错了
That is where you're wrong.
它名叫苍耳
Its name is the Xanthium.
带来了第二批汽车人
It bought the second wave of Autobots.
从那以后它一直由航空航天局看管和研究
And it's been under NASA's care and study ever since.
我们把它与一部退役的航天飞机相连
We've linked it with a decommissioned shuttle,
维持军管直至离开
to maintain military control until they're gone.
█
雷霆拯救队：汽车人成员
（上旋 灌铅脚 路霸）
雪佛兰 纳斯卡武装赛车
这颗小螺栓需要一万磅的扭矩
Gonna be 10,000 pounds of torque
不是19磅
on isty-bisty bolt... Oh, not 19.
你要敢拿我们的性命开玩笑  我就废了你
You're gonna risk the lives of all me mates! I'll ball you !
那几个就是雷霆营救队
That's your wreckers.
他们看管苍耳
They take care of the Xanthium.
我们不太让他们离开基地
We don't let them off the base much,
因为他们是一群混球
because they're assholes.
你应该拉那头  你这娘娘腔的贱人
You gotta pull that you Nancy wanker.
该干掉他了
It's time to kill him.
我只是想帮忙  尽职而已
I'm just trying to help, you know. Just doing my job.
冷静  别动他  他是人类
Calm down. Leave him alone. This is a human being.
-爱普斯  真是你 -你丫真蠢
- Epps. Is that you- You are ridiculous.
你好  伙计
what's up, man.
-你怎么在这  -我从空军退役了
-What are you doing here -I'm retired from the air force.
能放手吗
Can you let my hand go?
那是什么鬼东西
What the hell was that?
现在我只是给他们当顾问做后勤
I went on to just consult and run interference for them.
没有战斗
No more combat
没有外星人在背后攻击我
or alien shooting at my ass.
我得到了一份梦想职业
I got a dream job.
该离开这个星球了
Time to get off this planet.
要把汽车人赶走
Kicking the Autobots out.
你相信这是真的吗
Do you believe this is happening?
你认为要把他们送到哪
Where do you think is taking them?
除了地球  随便哪
Any planet but here.
我要找这里的负责人
I want to talk to whoever's in charge here.
夏洛特·米樱
Charlotte Mearing.
西蒙斯特工
Agent Simmons
前西蒙斯特工
Former Agent Simmons, so.
我看到你在华盛顿幸免于难
I see you survived Washington.
华盛顿  埃及  被人伤透心
Washington, Egypt, heartbreak.
我都没死  我以后也不会死
I survived, I will survive.
他们把所有人都卷进来了  孩子
They're bringing everybody in, kid.
把所有机器摆在桌子上
Putting all the Intel on the table.
如果你认为把九个汽车人送走
And if you think that putting 9 Autobots,
就能解决这破事
is going to solve a damn thing...
这我管不了
It's out of my hands.
平步青云  是吗
Moving up in the world, huh?
你那活真不错
Your booty looks excellent.
如果你告诉任何人
You ever say word to anyone
那晚在匡提科发生的事情
about what happened that night in Quantico.
我就把你的心挖出来
I'll cut your heart out.
我的心已经被你挖了
You already did.
塞米  听我说
Sammy, listen to me.
别让让他们驱逐我们
Don't let them exile us.
别让他们带走我们  山姆
Don't let them take us, Sam.
这是霸天虎的圈套
It's a Decepticon trap.
检查氮气  我们要从这里起飞
Checked the nitrogen, we're booting out of here.
擎天柱
Optimus.
你们首领说得对
What your leaders say is true.
都是我的错
This was all my fault.
我告诉他们要相信谁
I told them whom to trust.
我大错特错
I was so wrong.
这不是你的责任
It doesn't make your fault,
而是让你变得更加像人类
it makes you human for a change.
记住
Remember this.
你们可以对我们失去信心
You may loose your faith in us.
但千万别对自己失去信心
But never in yourselves.
我想知道你们怎样反击
I need to know how you're going to fight back.
我知道肯定有什么策略
I know there's a strategy.
我知道你们会带着援军回来
I know you're coming back with reinforcements.
我知道你们有计划的
Something, I know there's a plan.
你可以告诉我  不会有其他人知道
You can tell me, no other human will ever know.
没计划
There is no plan.
我们只是按他们的要求去做
We just do what they want,
我们自己怎么活下去
how are we going to live with ourselves?
你是我的朋友  山姆
You are my friend, Sam.
永远都是
You always will be.
但你们首领已经说了
But your leaders have spoken.
从今以后
From here.
你们只能独自战斗
The fight will be your own.
长话短说
Make it short.
我们要起飞了
We're loading up.
好了  快点  我们黎明启程
All right, hustIe up! We're launching at dawn.
我们要竭尽全力
We're gonna do whatever we can.
达成目标
make it like it was.
你永远是我的朋友
You will always be, my friend.
山姆
Sam.
我要走了
I gotta be going on.
多年以后  他们会问我们
Years from now, they're gonna ask us.
他们占领这星球的时候  你们在哪里
Where were you when they took over the planet?
我们回答说
We're gonna say.
我们只是袖手旁观
We just stood by and watched.
早上6:30
你应该把这看做合作
You should really look at this as a partnership.
如果你想被载入史册
You have to stand on the side of progress
就应该顺应潮流
if you want to be a part of history.
准备发射  五  四  三  二
Go launch in..5...4...3..2
一  零
1...zero.
加速
Go ahead and throttle up.
你想要答案吗  你有了
You wanted an answer. You got one.
我总是心想事成的  山姆
I always get what I want, Sam.
我们还要确认一下
We just needed to be sure.
确认什么
Sure of what?
他们不战而退
That they would go without a fight.
-再说一遍  -探测到外来物体
- Say again? - Detecting a foreign object.
我们现在全为霸天虎做事了
We all work for the Decepticons now.
芝加哥  伊利诺斯
我要你帮我追踪一个电话
I need your help to track a phone call.
电话那边是个男的  他是人类行动的头目
It's a man on this phone, he's the head of the human operation.
他挟持了卡莉做人质
And he's holding Carly hostage.
坐好  别动
Sit down, don't move.
我正看着他开过来
I'm watching him drive up right now.
已经锁定电话线路
The call was placed in-route.
我现在入侵电话的摄像头
I'm hacking into the phone's camera right now.
好了  从摄像头传回来的实时数据
There that is, that's a live stream from the camera.
什么地方  等等  我用三角定位
Someplace, hold on I can triangulate this.
好了  是芝加哥的基站
Okay, it's Chicago cell site.
那里  找到了
There, I got it.
川普大厦  芝加哥  稍矮的顶层公寓
Trump tower, Chicago, lower penthouse.
我们行动
We're on.
-我要去  -真的吗
- I'm going. - You're sure.
她都是为了帮我
She's done nothing but try to help me,
我十五个小时就能到那儿
I can be there in 15 hours.
你不会一个人去
You're not going alone.
那边还有我一些鸟巢部队的朋友
Still got my NEST friends out there.
我们召集他们
We'll round them up,
去救出你的女朋友  再抓到那坏蛋
find your girlfriend and bring this guy in.
为什么你要帮我
Why are you helping me?
因为那混蛋也杀了我的朋友
'Cause that asshole killed my friends, too.
他们说来这里是要我们的资源
They said they were here for our resources.
去重建他们的星球
To rebuild their planet.
是的  确切的说是一种特别的资源
Yes, really one resource in particular.
地球特有的
One unique to our planet.
我们
Us.
你真聪明
You're very smart.
没有奴隶的劳动力  他们无法重建
You see they can't rebuild without a slave labor force.
要发射多少火箭才能运送六十亿劳动力
How many rocks up there in the universe offer 6 billion workers?
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
我们不能运人
We can't transport people.
他们不是运人
They're not shipping people.
他们把他们的星球运到这里
They're shipping their planet here.
我的天
Oh, my God.
御天敌在这里做什么
What's Sentinel doing here?
看
Watch.
他们正在地球散布几百根传送柱
They're spreading hundreds of pillars around the globe right now.
几小时之后
In just a few hours.
把它们载入到轨道
They're going to launch them into orbit.
把赛博坦运到我们的大气层
And bring cybertron into our atmosphere.
红色的那根控制其他的传送柱
The red one there, controls the rest.
只要触发它  就会启动整个过程
He triggers that, it starts the whole thing.
蝼蚁工人滚吧  没你的事儿了
Be gone insect operative, your work is done.
是  阁下
Your Excellency.
你真不要脸
You're such a dick.
你希望这些发生吗
You want this to happen?
我想活  我还想多活四十年
I want to survive. I want 40 more years.
你认为我自找的吗
You think I asked for this?
我继承了个客户而已
I inherited a client.
是啊  当赛博坦运过来  我们都成了奴隶
Yeah, and when Cybertron's here and we're all their slaves
估计他们还是需要一位傀儡领袖
I guess they'll still need a human leader.
说白了  你要想活命就得听我的
Get this straight, you want to survive you listen to me.
是时候让地球奴隶们
It is time for the slaves of earth
认识一下他们的主人了
to recognize their masters.
封锁城市
Seal off the city.
把狗带走  带到后面来
Get the dogs out of here now, get them in the back.
我才他们没告诉你这部分  是吧
I guess they didn't tell you about this part, did they.
你觉得我都知情吗
You think I'm at every meeting?
他们承诺我的安全
They promised I'm safe.
他们说过我会没事
They said I'm safe.
出发
Let's roll.
刚才我们还有信号
We had a signal earlier
手机没用了
It's not working.
这是全国紧急广播
This is a national emergency broadcast.
芝加哥遭到攻击
Chicago has suffered a massive attack.
错误
Wrong way!
离开这  撤退
Get out of here! Go back!
芝加哥被外星人飞船包围了
There's a ring of alien ships around Chicago.
我们的远程轰炸机在空中被击落
Our high range bombers were just knocked out of the sky.
无法冲破敌人在城市上空的空中防御
They can't get through enemy air defenses over the city.
我们的卫星被破坏了
Our satellites have been jammed.
没法监控敌军的行动
We have no way to monitor the enemies movement.
全部鸟巢部队全部撤回
Our old NEST teams are on stand down.
驻守空军基地
holding at air force base.
离战区10分钟航程
10 minutes from the battle zone.
我们派出特种部队争取进城
We have special forces trying to gain access to the city.
一个步兵团往周边地区进发
An infantry is staging at the perimeter.
听我说  听我说  这真荒谬
Excuse me, excuse me, it just doesn't make sense.
我们就不能派眼线进去吗
Can't we get any eyes in there at all?
他们不停地击毁我们的无人战机
They keep shooting down our drones.
他们就是要我们看不见
They want us blind.
但我们还有几架小型遥控飞机可以一试
But we do have a couple of mini-drones we're gonna try.
告诉操纵这些无人机的人
Whoever's manning these UAV drones,
把它们导向川普大厦方向
...Can we try to redirect them toward, Trump Tower?
那小子威特维奇正赶往芝加哥
The kid, Witwicky was on his way to Chicago.
已经有小队的侦查人员奔霸天虎去了
Said some point-man human op is there for the Decepticons·
听着  据我所知
Listen, if I know anything, I know this.
那小子就是外星人的黑仔
That kid is an alien bad news magnet.
我的天
My God.
我们要在这种情况进城找她吗
We came here to find her in the middle of all that?
我们真要进去吗  爱普斯
Are we really going out there, Epps?
我不进去
I'm not going in there.
没人进去
No one's going in.
我去
I am.
有没有你们  我也要找到她
With or without you, I'll find her.
你这相当于自杀  山姆
You're gonna get yourself killed, Sam.
这就是你来的目的吗
Is that what you want?
你大老远跑来就是要送死吗
You came all the way out here to get yourself killed.
听到我的话了吗
Huh? Listen...to me what I'm saying.
她在这里全因为我
She's here because of me, do you understand?
听着  如果你进去
Listen, if you go in this building.
就算她还活着
That's if she's even still alive.
你也没法救她
There's no way you're going to be able to even reach her.
那你有什么好建议吗
Well what would you suggest I do.
结束了
It's over.
很遗憾  但都结束了
I'm sorry, but it's over.
不
No.
敌人来了
Woah, incoming!
我们会把他们全干掉
We will kill them all.
雷霆营救队  杀了他
Wreckers, kill him.
这肯定很疼
This is going to hurt.
绝对
A lot!
你们的首领现在应该明白
Your leaders will now understand.
霸天虎不会放过地球的
Decepticons will never leave your planet alone.
而我们要让他们以为我们已经走了
And we needed them to believe we had gone.
今天  以自由的名义
For today, in the name of freedom,
我们向他们宣战
we take the battle to them.
我看到你们的飞船炸掉了
I saw your ship blow up.
我们没上船
The ship, we were never in the ship.
这是我们设计好的
We designed the damn thing, didn't we.
我们躲在一级推进火箭里被分离出来
We were hidden in the first booster rocket to separate,
按计划落在大西洋
splashed down back in the Atlantic, just as planned.
我们哪都没去
We ain't going no where.
没人能驱逐我们
Yeah, no ones exiling us.
汽车人仍然留在这里
The Autobots are just staying right here.
我们要帮你们打赢这场仗
We're going to help you win this war.
他们环城形成防御
They're surrounding the city to make a fortress.
那样就没人看见他们在里面做什么了
So that no one can see what they're up to inside.
我们唯一的机会就是奇袭
Our only chance is the element of surprise.
我想我知道该去哪
I think I know where to look.
小型无人侦查机靠近川普大厦
Mini-drones on approach, Trump Tower.
你是要告诉我  山姆要进去吗
You're telling me, Sam's headed into that?
可怜的娃儿
Poor kid.
可能永远接近不了
Probably never got close.
你能开这东西  是吗
Your gonna fly this thing, right?
什么意思  那是什么意思
What does, what is that, what is that?
还凑合
So, so.
所以你还能凑合开
So you so, so can fly.
这太可怕了
That feels terrible.
我们支援你
We're right behind you.
好吧
All right.
我们进城
We're going in.
城市被封锁了
The city's secure.
人类无法阻止我们
The humans cannot stop us.
下午以后
As the afternoon falls,
剩下的传送柱会到达指定位置
the rest of the pillars will reach their launch position.
这就是我多年以前向你承诺过的胜利
This is the victory I promised you so many years ago
这就是我们一起重建赛博坦的地方
where we rebuild Cybertron together.
我屈尊同你合作是为了我们的星球能存活
I have deigned to work with you that our planet may survive.
我绝不会听命于你
I will never work for you.
你要是明智  就应该记得这差别
And you would be wise to remember the difference.
烦死我了  等得真心烦
Oh, I'm so sick of this. I'm sick of waiting.
她在哪
Where is she?
Where is she!?
你真是勇气可嘉
You've got some balls.
不  山姆
No, Sam!
不
No!
卡莉
Carly!
跳
Jump.
大黄蜂  开火
Bee, fire.
救他  大黄蜂
Help him, Bee.
汽车人  他们还活着
Autobots, they're alive.
汽车人他们在这里
They're here, Autobots.
霸天虎保护传送柱
Decepticons defend the pillar.
升起桥
Raise the bridges.
找到他们
Find them.
山姆
Sam.
你找到我了
You found me.
无论去哪我都相随
I'd follow you anywhere.
建立防御圈  我们走
Form a perimeter! Let's go, let's go
你疯了
Well you're crazy.
那是什么  那是我们的吗
What is that, is that us?
这是小型军用无人侦查机
This thing is a military UAV drone.
检查看看是否还能用
Check to see if it's still working.
可以  还有动力
Yeah, it's still got power.
飞机控制员  能收到吗
Flight control, do you copy?
可以转一下吗
Can you rotate?
随便做点什么
Can you do something?
我认为我们收到信号了
I think we got something.
爱普斯  看到爱普斯了
Epps, we got Epps.
给点反应
...do something.
拜托  动啊  动一下啊
Come man, work, work.
把音量放大
All right, turn the volume up on that.
是那小子
The kid
能转吗  给点反应
Can you rotate, something.
好了  好了
Yes, yes.
行了  他们能看见我们
Okay, okay they can see us.
芝加哥是一片废墟  明白吗
Chicago is ground zero, you understand?
-听得见我们吗  明白吗  -天
- You hear us, understand? - Jesus.
听好  御天敌在这里
Please listen. The Sentinel prime is here
而且他拿着建空间桥的传送柱
and he has the pillars for his space bridge.
他们在芝加哥河畔的一座建筑的楼顶
They're on top of a building on the Chicago river.
那楼属于霍奇基斯·古尔德投资公司
It's owned by Hotchkiss Gould Investments
操控一切的控制柱
The control pillar that controls everything.
就在东南的圆塔
In the southeast cupola.
你们得毁了那控制柱  必须把控制柱打下来
You gotta destroy the pillar. You have to shoot down the pillar.
否则他们就要把赛博坦运到这里了
Or they're going to transport Cybertron here,
明白吗
do you understand?
什么
What?
把那楼和无人侦查机的坐标给我
Give me the GPS on that building and on that drone.
走
Let's go.
测量坐标
Mensurate those co-ordinates.
缩短作战流程
Shorten the kill chain.
大家去跑道  五分钟之内出发
Guys on the tarmac, five minutes.
-东南方的圆塔  -就这样
- South east cupalar. - All right.
我们得在敌机发现之前转移
We need to move before the fighters spot us.
在这里等我们去找路
Wait here until we scout a route ahead.
我们走
Let's roll.
救护车  高空掩护
Ratchet, cover high.
可能用那火箭炮把控制柱打掉吗
Hey, think you could use that rocket to shoot down the pillar?
我们有八条街的距离
We're eight blocks away.
需要靠近点才能开火
We gotta get closer to take a shot.
不是靠近  而是要高点
Not closer, higher.
我们需要清晰的视线
We need clear line of sight.
而且是在河对岸
And it's across the river.
还需要时间偷偷地接近
Gonna have a hell of a time trying to sneaking up.
只有一发炮弹
We only got one shot.
一发就够了
One shot's all we need.
我们的能从地面观察那座楼
We gotta be able to see around that building from the ground.
让国家安全局发来那里所有摄像头的说明
Get NSA to send service specs for any cameras in that area.
可能还有几个能用
Maybe some are working.
交通灯  自动提款机  所有的
Traffic lights, ATM's anything.
听好了
Listen up.
你们想反击吗
You want to hit back?
我们要穿翼装进去
We're going to have a wing-suit in.
这是唯一的靠近方式
It's the only way to get close.
我不能向你们保证能平安归来
I can't promise anyone a ride home,
但如果你们和我一起去
but if you're with me...
现在世界需要你们
The world needs you now.
我会自己想办法平安归来  长官
I'll find my own ride home, sir.
还有谁
Who else?
我  长官
Right here, sir.
莫肖尔将军
General Morshower we're
请求在城南发起诱敌行动
requesting diversionary action to south of the city.
我们从北低飞
We're coming from north and low.
你们把敌人引向东方
You guys drive them to the east.
汽车人必胜  汽车人必胜
Autobot victory, Autobot victory.
必须警告你  外面那个霸天虎很吓人
Gotta warn you. That is one scary-ass Decepticon.
他们拿了我的拖车  我需要外挂飞行器
They got my trailer, I need that flight tech.
震荡波没法同时追杀我们所有人
Shockwave can't hunt all of us at once.
雷霆营救队  需要进行一次佯攻
Wreckers, we need a diversion.
-我们去干  -马上就去
- Let's get some. - You got that right.
听着  我们要绕到那玻璃楼
Listen, we're going to circle around to that glass building.
爬到足够高度来发射火箭炮
We'll get high enough to make the rocket shot.
你们去分散他的火力  走
While you guys draw his fire, let's move.
等一下
Wait a minute.
带上我发明巷战专用武器
I'm not going letting you go out there
再出发
without my urban-combat prototypes.
我们要出发  齐  得了
We gotta go, Que. Come on.
等等  这些是偷袭的好家伙
Wait, they're great inventions for kicking ass.
什么玩意儿
What are these?
那些是爆炸棒
Those are boom sticks.
三十秒内引爆
Armed in thirty seconds.
抓勾手套  攀爬用
Grapple gloves, for climbing.
-出发  -出发
- Move out, go on. - Move!
快走  快走
Go, go, go.
走  走
Move, move! Let's go.
走  快走
Let's go, come on.
你们要去哪
Hey, where you going?
-不  停下   -你们要去哪
- No, no, no. Stop, stop, stop. - Where you going?
-别走啊  -不能抛下弟兄啊
- Don't leave. - Never leave a bro behind.
震荡波来了
Aw, Shockwaves coming.
上楼梯
Go for the stairs.
爱普斯  这边走
Epps, this way.
右侧遇敌  右侧遇敌
Breaking right, breaking right.
明白  我们左侧迂回
Read, rolling left.
左侧我们也遇到一架敌机
We got another one coming around. Coming on the left side.
绕行右侧  绕行
Going around on to the right side. Going around.
我们利用威利斯大厦作掩护
We're going to use Willis Tower for cover.
一旦降到高度
Once we make altitude.
我们就跳
We jump.
-飞机很多  -敌人从机头离开
- A lot of airplanes out here!  - Contact off the nose
-求救  我觉得他没戏  -求救  求救
- Mayday I don't think he's going to make it. - Mayday, mayday.
一架运输机被击坠  -小心  小心
Six-one going down. -Heads up! Heads up!
老天保佑  老天保佑
Come on, come on, come on.
-塔利在左侧  -看到了
- Tally on the left.  - Got him
二十秒后到达目的地
Time on target, twenty seconds.
开始准备
Well here we go, here we go.
保持注意
Keep it tight.
他们飞过来了
coming around.
好了  精神集中  精神集中
All right, focus focus focus
敌人从塔上来  6点钟方向
Threat above tower, Six o'clock.
小喽罗
Locusts!
小心  右侧遭到攻击  右侧遭到攻击
Look out! breaking right! Breaking right
注意  注意
Watch out, watch out!
该死
Oh, shit.
小心  小心
Look out, look out, look out!
快让他们跳出去  快让他们跳出去
Get them out, get them out, get them out.
就现在  都出去  跳  跳
Now, Everybody out, out! Jump, jump, jump.
出去  快
Get out, get out.
我卡在这里了
I'm stuck
现在把他们都放出去
get them out now, get them all now.
救命
Help!
分散  保持路线
Get separation, track away, track away.
左转  左转
Hard left! Hard left!
离地600英尺
Six hundred feet.
注意六点钟方向
Check your six, Check your six.
他跟在我们后面
He's on our ass.
右转
Sharp right!
前面那栋楼是死胡同
Building, dead ahead.
我们穿过去
Thread the needle.
打开降落伞
Pull, pull!
行了  我们够高了
Hey come on we're high enough.
爬上来真特么累
This is a mother getting up here.
赶紧带着肥屁股滚过来
Get your fat ass over here.
就来
I'm coming.
装好火箭筒
Set up the rocket.
快点
Come on.
-他们来了  -武器状态
- They're coming. - Weapons status
29枚自动炸弹  20枚穿甲弹
29 Bot-busters, 20 piercing D-Bot
就是那  那座圆顶的楼
There, the building with the dome.
为了牺牲的兄弟们
For our brothers.
我们要让这次行动值回票价
Let's make this trip worth it.
老天
Oh, oh God.
楼怎么了   楼怎么了
Whoa, this building oh the building.
他们在向大楼射击
They're shooting at the building.
这不是个好主意
This is not a good idea.
什么
What?
这不是个好主意  这楼不稳
This is not a good idea, the building's not stable.
等等  如果我们来了却不达到目的
Just stop for a second. If we don't do what we came to do.
那就没意义了  反正我们都要死
Then it doesn't matter, we all die.
是吧  那就是目标  加油
Right? It's your target, come on man.
楼塌了我也不在乎
I don't even care if the building collapses.
反正我有心脏病
I'm having a heart attack anyway.
楼正往下倒
The building is going over.
-抓住   -找掩护
-Hang on. -Take cover.
把手举起来
Keep your hands up!
好了  停下了
It's okay, it's done.
大家  注意
Guys, look.
-敌人来了  -都藏起来
- Incoming, incoming. - Everybody hide.
别动
Don't...move.
跑
Run!
火力掩护
Cover fire.
打破窗户  跳出去
Shoot the glass, jump out the window.
跳
Jump.
我们要玩完了
We're gonna die
山姆  我停不了
Sam, I can't stop.
打碎玻璃
Shoot the glass.
山姆
Sam.
大家都没事吗
Is everyone okay?
你还好吗
You okay?
下面那是什么鬼东西
What the hell was that?
钻探兽要上场了
Driller-bot is thirsty
那个独眼怪看到我了
This evil thing is looking at me.
什么
What?
他还带着一个更丑的霸天虎
He's even got a uglier decepticon with it.
我们得撤出这栋楼
We have to evac!
-爱普斯队长  楼梯堵住了  -我们被包围了
- Sergeant Epps, the stairs are blocked. - We're trapped
我们怎么离开
Hey, how do we get out of here.
快点
Hey, come on.
上帝  只要让我活着离开
Oh lord, just let me get out of this alive.
我愿意把养老金全给你
I'll give you annuities, and get it together.
走  我们得离开
Move, we gotta move.
为什么霸天虎总是那么牛逼
Why do the Decepticons always get the good shit.
-走  -我们要变成别人的盘中餐了
- Move. - We're about to be eaten people.
我们要玩完了
We're gonna die!
-抓住  -给我你的手
- Hold on! - Give me your hand !
-我把你往那边甩  -接住她了
- I'm swinging that way! - Got her
我把你放到防火通道
I'm dropping you on the fire escape.
山姆
Sam!
天  我们快走
Whoa, we gotta move.
下去  快
Get down, move.
我来帮你们
I'm coming for you.
擎天柱
Optimus!
雷霆营救队
Wreckers.
我们来了
We're coming.
全世界的霸天虎
Decepticons around the world.
启动传送柱
Launch the pillars.
我们被丢弃了
Ahh, we are so lost.
我们总是被忽略
Always left out.
不错
Ka-ching
现在可以说了算了
It's time to lay down the law.
给他们点厉害看看
By to be the hurt now.
开始启动了
It's starting.
看到了吗
You see it.
小心
Look out!
山姆和卡莉去哪了
Where is Sam and Carly?
我们往这边跑
We can run this way.
我就交给你这一件事
I give you one thing to do.
就是看好他们  你竟然都搞砸了
One thing to do and you drop the ball on that.
我可从没答应承担这义务
I never signed for all of this.
外星人轰炸我  四处追我
Got aliens blasting me, running around chasing me.
我在教堂和建筑之间四处躲避
I'm ducking in churches and
穷于应付
buildings and all that kind of crap, maybe.
去你的吧  我可没答应这些  爱普斯
This is bullshit, I didn't sign up for this, Epps.
我尽力不让他们走散了
I'm trying to keep it together.
真是难得  就只有你们和我
What a treat, you and me.  Alone.
快  快跑
Come on, come on. Let's run.
他是在追我  不是你
Okay, he's after me not you.
快逃
Wait run, run.
臭小子  你无处可藏了
You can't hide, boy.
跑  快跑
Run, move it.
看你们忙着用小虫腿跑路
Love it when your little insect feet,
真是开心
...try to run!
-山姆  -快跑
- Sam! - Run!
本以为你还会为我们效力呢  小子
Thought you were working for us, boy.
山姆
Sam!
我的眼睛
My eye.
My eye!
看到霸天虎
Target the Decepticon.
山姆
Sam!
兰诺克斯  你们得救救山姆
Lennox you've got to save, Sam.
-你得救他  -他在干什么
- You've got to save him. - What is he doing?
最好这管用
This better work.
我看不见了
Ow, ow, ow. I can't see, I can't see.
山姆
Sam,
抓住我
take my hand.
这东西套在我手上  用刀
It's on my hand ! Grab the knife! Knife
-我在找  -刀  刀
- I'm trying! -Knife, knife, knife, knife, knife
你们这些人类
You humans.
炸弹还有二十秒爆炸
20 seconds for that bomb.
什么炸弹
What bomb?
看到了吗
See that boom.
-快割断  -看到了
- Cut it, cut it, cut it! -I got it
还有多长时间
How long do we have?
我要杀了
I'm gonna kill . .
快割
Cut, cut, cut!
他完蛋了
Well he's dead.
好了  大黄蜂去召集其他汽车人
Okay, he's going to run with
在河边和我们会合
the rest of the Autobots, meet us at the edge of river.
明白
All right.
他把我吸进来  我也没办法
He sucked me in, there was nothing I could do.
这里是霸天虎的集簇群
Uh oh. This is a total cluster form.
我们必须要过河
We gotta get across the river.
看那里
You see that?
卡莉说控制柱就在第一个圆塔里
She said the control pillar is in that first cupola.
走  我们行动
Go, move. Let's move.
战斧导弹已发射
Tomahawks are inbound.
预计二十分钟后到达
ETA, twenty minutes.
我入侵了交通摄像头
I'm in the traffic cameras.
有四个汽车人被抓住了
Four Aubobots are captured.
天啊  我们孤立无援了
Oh my God, we're helpless.
不管要发生什么  那些脉冲电流闪得更快
Whatever's set to happen. With those
都会马上开始
pulses getting faster it was going to happen soon.
没有看到擎天柱
No sign of Optimus.
怎么才能把桥放下
How do we get these bridges down?
散开  四处查看
Spread out, check in there.
爱普斯  我还在找你  你怎样
Epps, I've been looking for your ass. How you doing?
退休真烦  甚至更糟
Retirement is wack. Even worse.
我们无法过桥到对面那座大楼
We can't get across the river to that dude.
岸上的汽车人也全被包围了
And the Aubobots are upstairs surrounded.
移动镜头看下周围好吗
Just pan the camera around, all right.
好  右移  说你呢
All right pan, pan right, that's you.
派人去大桥控制室
Trying to get to that bridge control room.
他们在那里做什么  光站着不动
What are they doing there? They are just standing there.
等等  管家
Hang on, Dutch.
你能入侵大桥控制系统吗
See if you can hack into the bridge.
长官  海豹突击队到了
Sir, the seals are here.
大家好  你们什么情况
Oh it's a good day boys, what do you got?
长官  我们有10名队员
Got ten manned navy seal element sir,
任务是给战斧巡航导弹导航
and tasked with vectoring Tomahawks.
-导弹多久到   -十五分钟
- How long? - Fifteen.
-你们是战俘  -放松  我们投降
- You're my prisoners! - Take it easy. We surrender.
放开我
Get off me.
好了  你们带上
All right, you're gonna need your
MK-19 40毫米榴弹炮发射器和碎片弹
40 mike-mikes and frags.
切换到自动模式
Go for auto,
共振会阻断他们的电路
the vibrations jack up their circuits.
狙击手  射击他们的眼睛
Snipers, shoot for the eyes.
你们的目标在那座楼的楼顶
All right your target is up on top of that building.
那个圆塔
That cupola.
汽车人  你们注定要失败
How doomed you are, Autobots.
你们没能理解
You simply fail to understand.
为了多数人的需求
That the needs of the many,
要牺牲少数人的利益
out weigh the needs of the few.
激活空间桥
Activating the bridge.
他们正为什么高兴
They happy about something.
我们在他们太空船的中心
We're in the heart of their ship.
咱们来开下这飞船
Let's give him a little ride.
那我们可把这船毁了
Ho, ho we going to screw this ship up.
这是128K二进制加密
It's 128K binary inscription code.
很难
It's difficult.
但对我来说不是  我进去了
But not for me, I'm in.
大桥  放下
Bridge, down.
大桥降下来了
The bridge is coming down.
有人在帮咱们
Someone's watching over us.
西摩  很高兴与你合作
Pleasure working with you, Seymour.
我知道你会这么说
I believe you're suppose to say.
管家  干得好
Good job, Dutch.
谢谢
Danke schoen.
赶快  他们在启动传送柱
Hurry, they're triggering the pillars.
战俘  你们还留战俘吗
Prisoners, you're keeping prisoners?
是的
Yeeesss.
你得让他们学会尊重
You need to teach them about respect.
以前这都是生意
This was all business,
而现在是私人恩怨  明白吗
but now it's personal. Do you understand me?
明白
I understand.
不留战俘
No prisoners.
只要战利品
Only trophies.
大黄蜂  我认为他们要杀了我们
B, I think they're going to kill us.
你
You.
你该去死了
You're time is up.
等  等下
Wait, wait, wait.
我们已经投降了  我们是战俘
We surrender. We're your prisoners.
我们会
We give...
过去
Move it.
我们再谈谈行吗
Can't we talk this out?
我们都是棒小伙
We're all a bunch of good chaps.
我意思是...
I mean in all...unh!!!
你为什么
Why did you....
再见  我的老朋友
Goodbye my old friend.
你是我的了
You're mine now.
我得去救他
Gotta help him.
什么
What?
你要干什么
What are you doing?
我得救他
I gotta help him.
你救不了的
You can't help him.
山姆
Sam.
转过去
Turn around.
我们曾打得他们屁滚尿流
We, we never had it around.
成功了  里恩  我们成功了
We did it Brains. We did it.
把这条船拆了
Rip this ship apart.
-里恩  咱俩这招不错  -那是
- We...we had a nice run Brains, you and me. - Yeah.
我们也要完蛋了
We're gonna die.
小伙子们  跟我们走
Okay baby, you are coming with us.
我们走  你们
Let's go, you guys
跟着那只地面部队  快去
follow that ground team, go.
快  快
Move, move, move.
三楼了  我们要上到四十五层
Third floor, load up a 45.
好了  你们两个狙击手到那边
All right you two snipers right here.
好了  各就各位
All right, dock up.
我们三分钟后跳伞
We jump in three minutes!
在那布置火力点
Set the shot right here.
好的  准备
All right, set up.
我下楼
I'm downstairs.
震荡波和5个霸天虎在我们下方
We got five targets and Shockwave right below us.
准备跳伞
Stand by to jump!
好了  该我们了  准备
All right, let's go. Get ready, get ready.
跳
Go, go.
狙击手  射瞎他们的眼睛
Snipers, take out their eyes.
好了  爆破组安装炸弹
All right, Demo team lets crank steel.
即时引爆
Turning steel.
等我的命令开火
Don't fire until I tell you.
走
Go!
干的好
All right, good job.
-好的  -开火
- Yes. - Fire!
我们干掉他了
We got him.
是的
Yeah.
他逃跑了
He's on the run.
汽车人  攻击
Autobots, attack.
向那座桥开炮
Mortar that bridge.
现在这里属于我们了
It's our world, now.
开始传送
Commence transport.
我的天哪
My God.
擎天柱
Optimus!
你死定了
You die.
不
Nooo.
滚下来  御天敌
Get down here, Sentinel.
擎天柱
Optimus.
你忘记了自己的本分
You forget your place.
我在拯救你的故乡
I bring you Cybertron.
赛博坦
Your home.
而你仍然选择帮助人类
And still you choose humanity.
你告诉过我  追求自由是每个人的权利
You were the one who taught me freedom is everyone's right.
我会再次激活传送柱
I will retrigger that pillar.
那你得先踏过我的尸体
Then you'll have to go through me.
我得去帮忙
Okay, I got to help.
-不  你别去  -听我说
- No, you don't. - Listen to me now.
你会没事的
You're gonna be fine.
我保证  你会没事
I promised.  You're going to be fine.
我得去传送柱那里
I gotta get to that pillar.
去拿传送柱
Charge the pillar.
汽车人来了
We got Autobots.
走  快走
Move, move!
我需要支援
Reinforcements to me.
霸天虎飞船  向擎天柱开火
Decepticon ships, fire at Optimus.
我们受到攻击  现在需要战斧导弹
We are taking fire, I need those tomahawks here now.
第一波  到了
First wave, incoming.
我们得掩护擎天柱
We gotta cover for, Optimus.
霸天虎
Decepticons,
激活传送柱
trigger the pillar.
重新激活
Restart that pillar.
激活传送柱
Trigger the pillars.
我拦不住他们
I can't hold them.
我们被飞船卡在这里了
The ships have us pinned!
不
No.
逼近射程  还有10秒  进入射程
Inbound, ten seconds! Danger close.
马克利马  重复重复  14250
Mark-Lima-Echo-Echo, 1 4 2 50
-收到地面指示  -确认目标
- Found surface contact. - Got an ID.
锁定目标
Target acquired.
迪兰
Dylan!
-等等  -不
- Wait. - No!
-该死  -迪兰
- Shit. - Dylan.
住手
Stop, stop.
不
No.
你不能这样
You can't do this.
知道不
Okay.
我只有这条路
There's only one future for me.
赛博坦
Cybertron.
最终
You are saved.
你得救了
At last.
你是来投降的吗
Oh, have you come to surrender?
-这值得吗  -当然
- Was it all worth it? - Obviously.
你用尽全力救回了御天敌
All your work to bring Sentinel back.
现在他拥有至高无上的权利
And now clearly he has all the power.
你可真惨
It's actually almost tragic.
你竟敢教训我  奴隶
You dare lecture me, slave.
你们霸天虎最终将征服这个星球
Your decepticons finally conquering this planet.
但领袖不是你
And yet their leader wasn't you.
是我  一定是我
It will be me, it will always be me.
从此以后的每一刻
Any minute from now.
你什么都不是
You'll be nothing.
只是御天敌的婊子
You're Sentinels bitch.
发射
Rocket!
命中
Die!
你选了阵营
You chose sides.
却选错了
You chose wrong.
你一直都是我们中最勇敢的
Always the bravest of us.
但你却从未做过艰难的抉择
But you could never make the hard decisions.
现在
Now!
我们的星球将存活
Our planet will survive.
不
No.
我们都曾是神
We were Gods once.
我们每个人都是
All of us.
但现在
But here,
求你了
Please.
只能有一个神
They'll only be one.
这是我的星球
This is MY planet.
我拯救了另一个世界
I just saved a whole other world.
你认为你是英雄吗
You think you're a hero?
你认为你是英雄
Huh, you think you're a hero.
不
No.
我只是一个送信的
I'm just a messenger.
它还在传送
It's still connected.
把它停下
Bring it up!
-大黄蜂  我们来搞定  -过来  过来
- B! Let's do this! - Get going, get going. Let's move it.
太空桥还在传送
Oh it's still connected.
把传送柱放倒
Rip that pillar down!
不
No.
现在  我们可以停战
Now We need a truce.
我需要的只是重新掌权
All I want is to be back in charge.
再说
Besides...
没有我  你能做成什么
Who would you be without me?
擎天柱
Prime.
那就试试看
Time to find out.
擎天柱  我只是想
Optimus. All I ever wanted,
拯救我们的种族
was the survival of our race.
你要明白  我为什么得背叛你
You must see why I had to betray you.
你没有背叛我
You didn't betray me.
你背叛了你自己
You betrayed yourself.
不  擎天柱
No, Optimus!
山姆
Sam.
我爱你
I love you.
你是我在这世界的唯一
You're the only thing I need in this world.
我会尽一切可能补偿你  我保证
And I'll do anything to make it up to you, I promise.
我会记住你的承诺
I'm gonna hold you to that.
别再让我离开
Just never let me go.
我保证
Promise.
戒指
Rings.
我爱这辆车
I love this car.
但  你别这么心急
But, you gotta slow down.
慢点来  好吧
You gotta slow way down. Okay.
我只想帮忙
I'm just trying to help out.
在任何战争中
In any war.
暴风雨间总有安宁
There are calms, between storms.
-你战斗很勇敢  -有时我们会失去信念
- You fought bravely. - There will be days when we loose faith.
有时盟友会背叛我们
Days when our allies turn against us.
但我们绝不会
But the day will never come.
放弃这个星球
That we forsake this planet.
也不会放弃人类
And it's people.
导演
迈克尔·贝
这就是我所说的美好未来
That's what I called start of a beautiful future
逮捕他
Arrest him
-这也值了  -把他带走
- It's worthy it - Get him out of here
为爱我要进监狱  我不在乎
I'd go to jail for the love. I don't care.
我要进去  把我抓起来吧
I want going. Take me in. I want going. Let's going
来吧  夏洛特  现在就把我抓起来
Come on, Charlotte, take me in right now!